[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> Welcome to Stanford CS193p, Developing Applications for
> >欢迎来到斯坦福CS193p,开发应用程序
IOS, this is Winter quarter 2017,
IOS,这是2017年冬天的季度,
Today we are going to talk about a few things,
今天我们要谈论一些事情,
We're gonna start though giving a demo about what I
我们要开始虽然给我演示
talked about last time which is multiple MVCs,
上次讲多个mvc,
After that I'm gonna do some slides on the view controller
在那之后我要做一些幻灯片视图控制器
lifecycle, really important mechanism for finding out
生命周期,发现真正重要的机制
what's going on with your MVC as time goes flows by,
发生了什么和你的MVC随着时间的推移流,
And if I have time left at the end, I'm gonna start
最后,如果我有时间了,我要开始
talking a little bit about memory management,
说一点关于内存管理,
which is basically managing the memory of reference types,
这基本上是管理内存的引用类型,
things that are in the heap,
在堆中,
How do they get managed?
他们如何获得成功?
How do they know when the stay in the heap, or
他们怎么知道留在堆时,还是
leave the heap?
离开堆?
But first, we're gonna start with this demo,
但首先,我们要从这个演示,
I'm calling this demo emotions in FaceIt,
我打电话这个演示FaceIt情绪,
If you remember last time,
如果你还记得上次
we built a nice MVC that knows how to draw a face,
我们构建了一个漂亮的MVC,知道如何画一个脸,
It was a pretty generic MVC and
这是一个非常通用的MVC和
how to model, which is a facial expression,
如何建模,这是一种面部表情,
So now we're gonna build a more complicated app that has
所以现在我们要构建一个更复杂的应用程序
two MVCs,
两个mvc,
One MVCs is going to let you choose an emotion,
mvc是一个会让你选择一种情感,
Like happy or sad,
快乐或悲伤,
And then the other MVC is just gonna be our generic face
然后其他MVC只是要我们通用的脸
view, and it's gonna show that emotion,
视图,它会显示,情感,
we're gonna learn how to use the split view controller and
我们要学习如何使用视图控制器和分裂
By doing that,
通过这样做,
navigation controller, combine MVCs, to make a big graph,
导航控制器,结合mvc,产生很大的图,
It's a simple example because of time constraints but
这是一个简单的例子,但由于时间约束
you should get the idea,
你应该明白我的意思,
So here I'm back in FaceIt, this demo we had last time,
这里我回到FaceIt,上次这个演示,
One thing before I start,
一件事在我开始之前,
I wanted to show you something you're going to need for
我想给你你需要的东西
your homework, which is how to rename a ViewController,
你的家庭作业,这是如何重命名一个视图控制器,
I have this ViewController here,
我有这个ViewController,
This is the ViewController that shows the face,
这是ViewController显示的脸,
Remember, here's the faceView var and here's it's model,
记住,这是faceView var和这是它的模型,
So I don't like this name ViewController,
所以我不喜欢这个名字ViewController,
It's really quite too generic,
很太一般,
It's almost like it's super class,
就像它的超类,
which is UIViewController,
ui,
Really this wants to be some specifically named
真的想要一些专门命名
view controller, and in this case it shows a face so
视图控制器,在这种情况下,它显示了一个脸
this probably best called it faceviewcontroller,
这个最好称之为faceviewcontroller,
So I wanna just type face right here, and
我想这里的字体,
hope that's enough,
希望这就够了,
But of course as I mentioned in like lecture number one
当然,正如我喜欢演讲中提到的第一点
that's not enough,
这还不够,
You can't just rename right there,
你不能只重命名,
You actually have to rename a couple of other things,
要重命名其他事情,
One, the file that it's in, you see the file,
1的文件在你看到的文件,
is still called viewcontroller,swift,
还叫viewcontroller,迅速、
We almost always want to have our name of
我们总是想要的名字
our file be the same as the primary class that's in there,
我们的文件是相同的主类的,
Now, it's not required in swift, the name of the file
现在,不需要迅速、文件的名称
could be completely different than any class in there,
可能比任何类完全不同,
to kinda help people find the code that they're looking for,
有点帮助人们找到他们正在寻找的代码,
But generally,
但是一般来说,
we wanna have the name of the file pretty much match
我们想要文件的名称匹配
the name of the main class,
主类的名称,
It could be multiple classes in a short file,
在短文件,它可以是多个类
that's perfectly allowed as well, but
这是完全允许的,但是
especially if it is the main one,
尤其是如果它是主要的,
You might think, well that's enough, but
你可能会想,这就够了,但是
there's one more very,
还有一个非常
very important piece of this which is in the story board,
非常重要的这是在故事板,
We haven't really talked too much about this- well
我们还没有谈太多关于这个——好吧
actually, we did see it, with the Face View,
实际上,我们看到了它,面对视图,
We did this with Face View, but
我们做了这个脸视图,但是
we need to inspect this controller, and I'm
我们需要检查这个控制器,和我
gonna click on the controller by clicking this orange thing
要点击控制器通过点击这个橙色的东西
up here, that represents the controller for this whole MVC,
在这里,代表了整个MVC控制器,
'm gonna go over to this same inspector we went on when we
的要去同样的检查员的时候我们继续
changed the face view from being a generic UI view to
改变了视图从一个通用的用户界面视图
being a specific face view,
作为一个特定的视图,
'm gonna do the exact same thing here,
的要做相同的事,
So 'm picking this whole view controller and
所以挑选整个视图控制器和
'm going to the identity inspector up here and
的督察,身份
'm gonna change the class from ViewController,
从ViewController会改变类的,
that's what it was the generic name to Face view controller,
这就是它是脸视图控制器的通用名称,
So if you forget to do this piece,
如果你忘记做这一块,
than none of your outlets are gonna be hooked up,
比没有要挂你的网点,
And iOS is gonna be very confused because you're
和iOS是会非常困惑,因为你
gonna be asking it to couple outlets to a different class,
要问它几家不同的类,
SomeClasses doesn't exist anymore cuz I renamed it away,
SomeClasses不存在了因为我重命名,
You'll need to do that for your homework,
你需要做你的家庭作业,
You'll have to change your current calculator
你必须改变你目前的计算器
MVC from being called View Controller
MVC的视图控制器
to being called something like Calculator View Controller and
被称为类似计算器控制器和视图
that's because you're gonna have this new MVC- the graph
这是因为你会有新的MVC -图
view controller- and you wanna make clear which one is which,
视图控制器——你想明确哪个是哪个,
Now I'm not gonna touch my Face View Controller or
现在我不会碰我的脸视图控制器或
MVC at all in this demo from here on,
在这个演示MVC从这里开始,
I'm gonna build this multi-MVC app, and
我要建造这个multi-MVC程序,
I'm gonna use the face view controller that I just
我将使用我的脸视图控制器
finished building last time as a reusable component,
上次完成建筑作为一个可重用的组件,
Just like your graph view
就像你的图形视图
controller is gonna be a reusable MVC in your homework,
控制器是一个可重用的MVC作业中,
I said that I wanted to have two MVCs,
我说,我想有两个mvc,
One is just a list of some emotions,
一个只是列出了一些情感,
And then I'm going to use this MVC to show that emotion,
然后我将使用MVC表明情感,
So let's just dive right into this and
我们潜水到这
put another MVC into our storyboard,
另一个MVC放入我们的故事板,
We have this one MVC, we get another one, in exactly
我们有这一个MVC,得到另一个,完全
the same way that we get a new button or something like that,
同样的方法,我们得到一个新的按钮之类的,
which is to go down here to the utilities window
这是去下面工具窗口吗
at the bottom here and just drag out a view controller,
在底部就拖出一个视图控制器,
You just pull it out and
你只是把它出去
drag it right into your storyboard like that,
把它拖到你的故事板,
Now this MVC right here,
现在这里的MVC,
what's gonna be its class of it's controller?
什么是它的类的控制器吗?
It's just going to be (if we select it by clicking on
这就是(如果我们通过点击选择它
the orange thing), UI view controller,
用户界面视图控制器,橙色的东西)
In other words not a sub class,
换句话说不是子类,
So we're gonna need to create a custom sub class for
所以我们将需要创建一个自定义子类
this view controller just like we have for
这个视图控制器就像我们一样
our face view controller,
我们的脸视图控制器,
We'll do that in a second,
我们会做这个,
Before we do that though,
我们所做的,虽然之前,
I wanna talk about this little arrow,
我想谈谈这个小箭头,
You see this arrow right here?
你看到这个箭头吗?
This is the arrow that tells iOS when this app launches,
这个箭头告诉iOS启动这个应用程序时,
use this MVC as the first thing that appears,
使用这个MVC作为第一件事出现,
It's like the "entry" into the storyboard,
就像“条目”故事板,
And so if I want it to be the other one,
所以如果我想要另一个,
I can just pick it up with the mouse,
我可以把它捡起来用鼠标,
And drop it on that one,
并把它放在一个,
And now this one is my entry MVC,
现在这个是我进入MVC,
I also want you to notice that we have a warning here,
我也想让你注意到这里有一个警告,
You see this yellow warning?
你看到这个黄色的警告吗?
I'm gonna click on that,
我要点击,
and we'll see here it says face view controller is
我们会看到它说面视图控制器
unreachable, because it has no entry points,
遥不可及的,因为它没有入口点,
It's saying this view controller right here with
它说这个视图控制器
the face, you're never gonna see that in your app,
的脸,你不会看到,在你的应用,
Which is true, because my app is gonna come in here to this
这是真的,因为我的程序会在这里呢
blank one and I can't get to the FaceView from there,
空白的一个,我不能得到FaceView从那里,
Now of course we're going to add SplitView controller,
当然我们会添加SplitView控制器,
and navigation controllers, and we're eventually gonna be
和导航控制器,我们最终会
able to get there, but I just want you to understand what
能够到达那里,但我只是想让你明白
this unsupported configuration means,
这个不受支持的配置手段,
It just means that you can't get there,
它只是意味着你不能到达那里,
If I move this back, this arrow off of this and
如果我移动这个回来,这箭的
back over to here, now this one, you see,
在这里,现在这一个,你看,
view controller is unreachable,
视图控制器是遥不可及的,
Which makes perfect sense,
很有道理,
If I run this app by the way, let's go ahead and run, you're
如果我运行这个程序,让我们来运行,你
gonna see that my app's gonna come up completely blank,
会看到我的应用程序会出现完全空白,
That face will not be there because that MVC is
不会,因为那张脸,MVC
really not even being used,
真的没有被使用,
It's in the storyboard right now, but
现在在故事板中,但是
since it's not accessible we can't navigate to it,
因为它不是我们不能导航到它,可
We can't segue to it to use the terminology you
我们不能继续使用的术语
learned last time,
最后一次,
We get this completely blank UI,
我们得到了这个完全空白的UI,
If we want to have things like outlets and actions,
如果我们想要拥有网点和行动,
or anything like that, with this View Controller, it needs
或类似的东西,这个视图控制器,它需要
to have a custom subclass of UI view controller,
有一个自定义子类的UI视图控制器,
it can't just be generic,
它不能仅仅是通用的,
So we're gonna create that,
所以我们要创建,
We're gonna go to File, New File, remember that's always
我们要去文件,新文件,记住,总是
where we go when we create a new UI View Subclass,
去哪里当我们创建一个新的用户界面视图子类,
a new UI View Controller, any Calculator brain,
一个新的用户界面视图控制器,任何计算器大脑,
We did all those from new file,
我们做了所有这些新文件,
So I'm gonna click new file,
所以我要点击新文件,
This is gonna be a sub class of a UI view controller,
这是一类子UI视图控制器,
I'm gonna pick this one here, cocoa touch class,
我要选这个,可可触摸类,
We use swift file over here when it was just
我们使用快速文件时
calculator brain, not a sub class of anything,
计算器的大脑,而不是a类的东西,
But here, we're gonna do cocoa touch class,
但在这里,我们要做可可触摸类,
And it says subclass of what?
和它的子类说什么?
Okay, it's even defaulted here to UIVewController,
好的,甚至违约UIVewController,
Remember earlier we picked UIView,
还记得我们选择UIView早些时候,
We're gonna leave this UIViewController and I'm gonna
我们要离开这个ui和我要
call this view controller my EmotionsViewController,
叫我EmotionsViewController这个视图控制器,
So this gonna show the emotions like happy,
这将显示情绪如快乐,
sad, whatever, and
难过的时候,无论,
then I'm gonna click on it to go show the face,
然后我要去点击它显示的脸,
So I just do that,
所以我就这样做,
Go over here, it says where do you wanna put it,
在这里,你想把它放在哪里,
Again, I do not wanna put it here,
再一次,我没有想要把它放在这里,
You see where it says Group FaceIt, and
你知道它说组FaceIt和
it has that blue icon,
它有蓝色的图标,
We wanna put it down in here,
我们想把它放在这里,
So if you put it here,
如果你把它放在这里,
it's gonna be at the very top level,
它会在最顶层,
Down here, it's with all your other classes space
下面,与所有其他类空间
faceview,swift, etc,
faceview、迅速等,
So make sure you remember to do that,
所以一定要记住,
So here I popped it in there,
这里我出现在那里,
There's my view controller selected in the navigator,
这是我的视图控制器在导航器中选择,
Let's make the navigator a little bit wider, so
让导航器有点宽,所以
you can read it, there we go,
你可以阅读它,好了,
EmotionsViewController and
EmotionsViewController和
you can see it's giving me a little bit of code,
你可以看到它的代码,给我一点
These right here are part of the ViewController life cycle,
这些在这里ViewController生命周期的一部分,
which I promise I'm gonna talk about right after this
我承诺我要讲这之后吗
but not now,
但不是现在,
There's this other thing that's commented out down
这是有另一件事是注释掉了下来
here, which is actually really important to today's lecture,
,这其实是非常重要的今天的课程,
This is Navigation method,
这是导航方法,
which you know all too well from last lecture,
从上节课,你非常清楚,
It's called prepare for segue,
它叫做准备segue,
This is the method that's gonna be used when we segue or
这种方法是当我们segue或使用
transition from this MVC to another one,
从这个MVC过渡到另一个,
And we have to prepare that other one to do its job and
我们必须准备,另一个做它的工作
here's why we do it, prepare for segue,
这就是为什么我们这样做,准备继续,
We'll be coming back and implementing prepare for
我们会和实施准备回来
segue, in just a minute,
segue,仅仅一分钟,
Now that we have this new class, EmotionsViewController,
现在我们有一个新类,EmotionsViewController
we have to do the exact same thing we just did,
我们必须做同样的事,
Which is to go back to our storyboard,
这是回到我们的故事板,
click on this View controller, go to the Utilities window,
点击这个视图控制器,去公用事业窗口,
get that identity inspector up,
得到身份检查员,
And then pick the class in EmotionsViewController, so
然后选择EmotionsViewController中的类,所以
that this is now an EmotionsViewController,
这是现在一个EmotionsViewController,
not a generic UIView controller,
没有一个通用的UIView控制器,
So now that we've hooked that up,
现在我们已经连接,
we can start building our UI here,
我们可以开始构建UI,
What is our UI here?
我们的UI是什么?
It's gonna be super simple,
它会是超级简单,
I'm just gonna grab some buttons, so
我要抓住一些按钮
let's get one here,
让我们一个在这里,
let's change some attributes of that button,
让我们改变一些属性的按钮,
How about let's make the font really big,
如何让字体很大,
something like 40 point is probably good,
40点可能是好的,
Let's go ahead and make some more of them,
让我们来做一些更多的人,
I'm gonna copy and paste,
我要复制粘贴,
I think three of them is enough for this demo,
我认为他们三个是足够的对于这个演示,
We'll have one of our emotions be sad, another emotion be
我们有一个我们的情绪会难过,另一种情感
happy and I don't know if this is an emotion but
快乐,我不知道这是一种情感
we'll have this one be worried,
我们会有这个担心,
Those are gonna be our three things we're gonna show
那些是我们的三件事我们要表演
with our face,
与我们的脸,
view, let's put a little space in between them there,
看来,我们把一个小空间在他们之间,
We'll fill equally even though they're all buttons, so
我们将填补同样即使他们所有按钮,
they're all gonna be filled equally anyway,
他们都要满同样不管怎样,
So we've got this nice stack view right here,
所以我们有这个好堆栈视图,
Now, one thing about this stack view is, if I put it
现在,有一件事关于这个堆栈的观点是,如果我把它
here and I go down to look at my various orientations and
我去看我的各种各样的取向和
devices, if I go landscape here, "Ugh!",
设备,如果我去,“啊!”
It gets cut off, right?
它被切断了,对吧?
So I really want these, this stack to stay in the middle,
所以我真的想要这些,这堆保持在中间,
I don't wanna do the same thing I did with
我不想做同样的事情
the calculator where I'm sticking it to the edges,
计算器,我把它的边缘,
I just want it to stay in the middle cuz I don't want
我只是想让它呆在中间因为我不想
the buttons to be kinda really spread out,
按钮是真的有点分散,
I want them to stay kind of collected but
我想让他们保持收集但
I want them in the middle,
我希望他们在中间,
I can still do that with the autolayout,
我仍然可以做到自动布局,
the same way we did in the last demo,
同样我们在过去的演示,
I'm just gonna pick up the thing and
我要捡起东西,
use the blue lines to indicate what I want,
用蓝线显示我想要的,
Which is I want this in the center,
我希望这个中心,
I'm holding this, so
我拿着这个,所以
that the blue lines come on in the center,
蓝线的中心,
And when I let go, iOS interface builder here knows "
当我放手,iOS界面构建器知道”
he wants that in the center",
他希望,在中心”,
So that when I go down here to this little guy again and
所以当我再次去下面这个小家伙
I say reset to suggested constraints,
我说重置建议约束,
just like I did in the last lecture,
就像我在上一节课,
it creates constraints that put it in the middle,
它创建约束,把它放在中间,
And we can verify that by going up to this inspector,
我们可以确认,检验员,
this is the size inspector,
这是尺寸检查器,
It shows the size of the thing but
但是它显示的大小事情
it also shows the constraints, the autolayout constraints,
它还显示了约束,自动布局的限制,
And this is constrained to align its center horizontally
这是限制水平使其中心
to the superview center and
父视图中心
it's centered vertically to the superview center,
它的父视图中心居中,
Now if we do the rotation,
如果我们做旋转,
we see that it stays in the center,
我们看到它呆在中心,
I'm giving you a little taste of autolayout,
我给你一个小的味道自动布局,
I'm gonna give a whole lecture on autolayout
我要给一个整体讲自动布局
in a couple weeks,
在几周,
But I'm just trying to give you a little hint
但是我只是想给你一个小提示
about how it works for now,
关于它是如何工作的,
Alright, so we have this, this is our UI,
好的,我们有这个,这是我们的用户界面,
that's the entire UI that we're gonna do,
这是整个UI,我们要做的,
Now let's go ahead and run this,
现在让我们继续运行这个,
run it on iPhone briefly here
在iPhone上运行它短暂
Just to make sure that we've actually put this in our UI,
为了确保我们的UI,已经把这个
There it is, Sure enough if I click on it,
在这里,当然如果我点击它,
rotation, seems to work fine,
旋转,似乎工作好,
We can even check to see, does this work on iPad?
我们甚至可以查看,这在iPad工作吗?
Let's try this one now right there,
现在让我们试试这个,
Here it is, here's our UI,
在这里,这里是我们的UI,
It's working fine here and we can rotate here as well and
这里的工作很好,我们可以在这里和旋转
get this gigantic landscape iPad,
得到这个巨大的景观iPad,
Is there any way to go smaller?
有什么方法去小吗?
What's the smallest we can go scale?
我们可以去最小的规模是多少?
25%?
There we go, that's small enough,
好了,这是足够小,
So we've got all this screen real estate here on an iPad,
所以我们有这一切在iPad屏幕,
It's be really great to use the split view to have these
这是非常伟大的使用这些拆分视图
words on the left and the face that matches it on the right,
左边和右边的脸相匹配,
So that's exactly what we're gonna do,
这正是我们要做的,
we're gonna go back to our storyboard right here and
我们将回到我们这里的故事板
make that happen,
使发生,
And to do that, again, is just a matter of dragging something
为此,再一次,只是一个拖东西的问题
out, I'm gonna make my scale really small here, so
,我要让我的规模很小,所以
you can see this as we drag it out,
你可以看到这是我们拖出来,
But here we're gonna drag out the split view controller
但是在这里我们会拖出分割视图控制器
cuz we wanna put these two MVCs in an MVC
因为我们想把这两个在MVC MVC
that has them as part of its view,
他们的观点,
So when I drag this out, you're actually
所以当我拖出来,你
gonna see I get more than just a split view,
会看到我得到的不仅仅是拆分视图,
I get some other little MVCs that come along with it here,
我得到一些其他小mvc,随之而来,
And I don't really need any of these other
我不需要任何其他的
MVCs that come along with it,
mvc,随之而来
Trying to make your life easier, but
试图让你的生活更容易,但是
I find that 99% of the time,
我发现99%的时间,
you don't need these other things that come with it,
你不需要其他东西来,
So I'm just going here and select those and delete them,
所以我要选择那些和删除它们,
So let's get rid of this one,
那么让我们摆脱这个,
Whoops! Not the whole thing,
哎呀!
Let's just get rid of this one,
让我们摆脱这个,
sorry, there and we're gonna get rid of this one and
对不起,我们要摆脱这个和
we get rid of that one,
我们去掉一个,
I'm just left with my split view controller and,
我只剩下分割视图控制器,
of course, my two MVCs are here,
当然,我的两个mvc在这里,
Let's move this little more over to the side here,
让我们移动这一点在这里,
scroll down a bit,
向下滚动,
And now I just wanna make this be the master of my split view
现在我只是想让这个被拆分视图的主人
controller and I want this to be my detail,
控制器和我想这是我的细节,
Whoops, other way around,
哎呀,相反,
this is the master, this is the detail,
这是主人,这是细节,
When the app starts, I don't want it to start here,
当应用程序启动时,我不想让它从这里开始,
I want it to start here, don't forget this step,
我想要从这里开始,别忘了这一步,
If you want the app to come here and
如果你想让这个应用程序来这里
then show the split view controller with both things,
然后用两个东西,显示分割视图控制器
So how do I make this the master and this the detail?
所以我怎么做这个主和这个细节吗?
I'm just gonna hold down control and
我要抑制和控制
drag from the split view controller to the master,
拖动分割视图控制器的主,
And then in here,
然后在这里,
Only these two, master and detail,
只有这两个,主和细节,
So I'm gonna make that one the master,
所以我要做一个主人,
it makes this little master connection there,
它使这个小主人的联系,
that's not a segue by the way, that's a kind of like,
这不是一个segue顺便说一句,这是一个有点像,
somewhat like an outlet connection but
但是有点像一个出口连接
it's a specific connection to that master var there,
这是一个特定的连接,主var,
This one is the detail,
这是细节,
So I've made my master and my detail here,
所以,我做了我的主人和我的细节
Zoom in a little bit,
放大一点,
That's really all I need to do to get these both on screen,
这就是我需要做的所有这些都在屏幕上,
So let's go ahead and run and see what happens here,
让我们继续运行,看看会发生什么,
Alright, so here we go,
好吧,我们走,
Sure enough, there's the face on the right,
果然,右边的脸,
Here's this stuff on the left,
这是左边的这个东西,
And if I click this, nothing happens,
如果我点击这个,什么事也没发生,
The face doesn't show,
面对没有显示,
Now why does nothing happen there?
现在为什么没有发生?
Because we have to do the step of having a segue,
因为我们要做的一步segue,
If we want to move to a different MVC,
如果我们想要搬到一个不同的MVC,
we have to segue to it,
我们必须继续,
Each of these is gonna have to have the segue to this MVC,
这些是要有segue MVC,
And when it segues, it's gonna replace that MVC with a new
当它而已,它会用一个新的替换,MVC
one that's properly prepared to show that motion,
一个正确的准备运动表明,
Let's go do our segues,
让我们去做而已,
Segues also of course,
当然,segue也
we use our favorite gesture which is Ctrl + drag,
我们使用Ctrl +拖我们最喜欢的姿势,
So if I wanna make a sad segue, I'm just gonna hold
如果我想做一个悲伤的继续,我要
down Ctrl and drag it to the MVC that I want to segue to,
按住,并将其拖动到MVC,我想继续
the MVC I want to show when I press Sad,
MVC我想给在我难过的时候,
So I do that,
所以我这样做,
Now, you notice that I have some choices of what
现在,你注意到我的一些选择
kind of presentation, what kind of segue I want,
的演讲中,什么样的segue我想要的,
For example, Present As Popover would present
例如,目前为弹出窗口将礼物
the thing I'm segueing to in a little popover window on
这件事我segue弹出窗口
top of everything else,
别的不说,
Present Modally would take over the whole screen and
现在的语气地将接管整个屏幕
show the new MVC,
显示新的MVC,
Then there's show and show detail,
还有表演,展示细节,
Show is only used when you're in a navigation controller,
显示只有当你在导航控制器使用,
the thing where they've got the cards sliding on top,
的事情,他们有卡片上滑动,
like the settings example I showed you,
我给你看像设置的例子,
Show detail is used in a split view setting or in a hybrid
显示细节是用于拆分视图设置或混合
setting, where sometimes you're in a split view, and
设置,有时你在拆分视图,和
sometimes you're in navigation view,
有时你在导航视图,
which is gonna be the case that we're gonna be in here,
会是这样,我们将会在这里,
Show detail means show this in the detail side of
显示细节意味着显示详细的一面
the split view,
拆分视图,
I'm gonna show detail there,
我要展示的细节,
I've made this segue, you see it appeared right here,
我做了这个segue,你看到它出现在这里,
This is a segue,
这是一个继续,
looks a little different from this thing,
与这个东西看起来有点不同,
a little different icon right there,
有点不同的图标,
This is a segue and you can click on it, and
这是一个继续,你可以点击它,和
in fact you can even inspect it,
事实上,你甚至可以检查它,
And you must inspect it, in fact,
事实上,你必须检查它
go to the attributes inspector and inspect it, because you're
属性检查器和检查它,因为你
always gonna wanna give every segue an identifier,
总是会想给每个segue一个标识符,
This is just a unique string, that in your code you'll
这是一个独一无二的字符串,你会在你的代码
be able to reference in order to say,
可以参考以说,
"I'm talking about this segue right here",
“我说的是这里的segue”,
So, I'm gonna call this my sad segue,
所以,我称之为我的悲伤segue,
Then I'm gonna do the exact same thing here for happy,
然后我要做一样的快乐,
I'm gonna just show detail on that one,
我要展示细节,
I'm gonna inspect that segue,
我要检查segue,
See, there's our sad one,
看,这就是我们的悲哀,
Notice that when you pick a segue,
注意,当您选择一个segue,
it shows you what it's segueing from,
它显示你的segue,
If I pick this one, it shows it seguing from the other one,
如果我选择这个,它显示了它从另一个,哪一
so we know which one it is,
我们知道它是哪一个,
So this is the happy one, and
这是幸福的一个,
then we'll have our little worried segue,
然后我们会有我们的小担心segue,
Where's that one?
一个在哪儿?
It's right there, worried,
在这里,担心,
Okay, so that's it,
好吧,就是这样,
So we've created these segues, put them in the, we'll put it
我们已经创建了这些而已,把它们放在,我们将把它
into split view first, then we created the segues,
到先拆分视图,然后我们创建了而已,
And now when you click on those buttons,
现在当你点击这些按钮,
it's going to segue to this detail and in fact in a split
它会继续这个细节和事实上的分裂
view it replaces the one that's there with a new one,
把它取代了一个有一个新的,
Remember that segues always create a new one,
记住,segue总是创建一个新的,
Don't forget that, that segues always create a new one,
别忘了,segue总是创建一个新的,
Something easy to forget,
容易忘记的东西,
Especially in the split view, it looks like,
特别是在拆分视图,它看起来像,
" it just changed the one that was already there",
“这只是改变了一个已经存在”,
But no, it actually just completely replaced that
但它实际上完全取代
detail segue by doing that,
细节segue通过这样做,
If we run this it it's gonna look like
如果我们运行这个它它会是什么样子
it doesn't didn't even work,
它不甚至不工作,
Even though we hooked these segues up,
即使我们连接这些segue,
it looks like it's just not doing anything, watch,
看来是不做任何事,手表,
Okay, so is he sad, happy, worried, nothing is happening,
好的,所以他是伤心,高兴,担心,什么也没有发生,
Absolutely nothing is changing over here,
绝对没有什么变化,
Now, what's interesting is it is in fact seguing, and
现在,有趣的是它实际上是哪,和
it is replacing that,
它正在取代,
The only problem is, we didn't prepare that thing
唯一的问题是,我们没有准备的东西
to show the right emotion before it showed, so
显示正确的情感才显示,
it is just showing the neutral emotion,
它只是显示中性情绪,
It's creating a new MVC, but it's just showing neutral,
创建一个新的MVC,但它只是显示中性,
because it has not been prepared to be onscreen,
屏幕上,因为它还没有准备,
We have to go back to the emotions view controller here,
我们必须回到这里的情绪视图控制器,
and do this prepare for segue, and prepare that destination
做这个准备segue,准备目的地
detail view controller to do what we want it to do,
细节视图控制器做我们想要做的,
Let's get rid of some of the comments here,
让我们摆脱这里的一些评论,
just to make our code a little cleaner,
为了让我们的代码更干净一点,
And get rid of that, as well,
和摆脱,
Actually, we can even get rid of that,
实际上,我们甚至可以去掉,
Okay, so here's our prepare for
好的,这是我们的准备
segue with this extra argument sender,
继续使用这个额外的参数发送者,
which I'll also talk about in a little bit,
我还将讨论在一点,
So what do we do when we prepare for segue?
所以我们做什么当我们准备segue ?
There's usually two really important piece of information
通常有两个非常重要的信息
we need when we're preparing to segue to an MVC,
我们需要当我们准备segue MVC,
One is we need to know which segue, tha's the identifier,
一个是我们需要知道这segue,那是标识符,
The other one we need to know is what is the new MVC
另一个我们需要知道的是什么是新的MVC
that this system just created for
这个系统刚刚创建的
us that we're supposed to prepare,
我们,我们应该准备,
Both of these things are found inside this
这两个东西在里面
argument right here, this segue, this UIStoryboardSegue,
论点,这个segue UIStoryboardSegue,
if we ALT click on it,
如果我们ALT点击它,
Can't get it,
不能得到它,
Sorry about that, here we go, on this guy,
抱歉,我们开始吧,这个家伙,
We have the storyboard segue, and
我们有故事板segue,
if you'll look in the documentation for it,
如果你看它的文档,
you'll see that it doesn't have a lot in there,
你会发现它没有很多,
But one important thing is the destination view controller,
但重要的是目标视图控制器,
and one is the identifier of the segue,
一的标识符是segue,
This is also the source,
这也是源,
which would be the emotions view controller,
这将是情感视图控制器,
That's really just got the information
只是得到信息
that we need to prepare this thing,
我们需要准备这个东西,
Let's go and first get the destination view controller,
让我们去第一个目标视图控制器,
I'm gonna say let destinationViewController
我要让destinationViewController说
equal the segue's destination,
平等segue的目的地,
So I've got that view controller,
所以我有视图控制器,
Now that is a type UI view controller, if I alt-click on
现在是一个类型的UI视图控制器,如果我alt-click
that, you'll see it's type UI view controller,
,你会看到它的类型的UI视图控制器,
That's because segue is this generic UI stroyboard thing,
这是因为segue这是通用UI stroyboard的事情,
it doesn't know anything about face view controllers,
它不知道任何关于视图控制器,
EmotionViewController, anything like that,
EmotionViewController类似,
So, we're gonna have to actually use that casting
所以,我们要实际使用铸造
mechanism with as,
机制,
Remember that as casting that we did with Any, in AnyObject?
记住,铸造我们做任何,AnyObject吗?
We're gonna have to do it here,
我们这里要做,
because this destinationViewController
因为这destinationViewController
better darn well be a face view controller, or
更该死的是一个面临视图控制器,或
I don't know how to prepare it,
我不知道如何准备它,
That's the only thing I know how to prepare,
这是我唯一知道如何准备,
this emotion for us, so it'd better be that,
这对我们的情感,所以它最好,
So I'm gonna say, if I can let a FaceViewController equal
所以我想说,如果我能让FaceViewController相等
the destinationViewController as, and
destinationViewController,和
I'm gonna do it conditionally here, a FaceViewController,
我要做有条件地在这里,FaceViewController,
Then, I'm good to go,
然后,我很好,
So now remember, this as kinda conditionally checks to see if
现在请记住,这是有条件地检查
it's possible for this to be a FaceViewController,
可能这是一个FaceViewController,
And if it's not, my preparer's gonna do nothing,
如果它不是,我填表人会什么都不做,
And it's gonna let that destination view controller
它会让目标视图控制器
appear unprepared,
显得措手不及,
because it doesn't know how to prepare it,
因为它不知道如何准备它,
Cuz we only know how to prepare, (at least so far in
因为我们只知道如何准备,(至少到目前为止
our app), we only know how to prepare a FaceViewController,
我们的应用程序),我们只知道如何准备一个FaceViewController,
Okay, in fact some would say don't use, as, with,
好吧,事实上有些人会说不用,,,
if let, here,
如果我们,在这里,
Just use as exclamation point, and make your program crash if
只使用感叹号,如果让你的程序崩溃
you try to segue to something you're not expecting,
你尝试segue一些你不希望,
Cuz again, you'll find it when you're debugging
因为再一次,你会发现它当你调试
before you ship your product,
在你船你的产品,
So I can see the argument for that,
所以我可以看到的理由,
But we'll make it so we'll just ignore it, if we can't
但我们会让我们忽略它,如果我们不能
convert that destination to a face view controller,
该目的地转换为一个视图控制器,
Alright, so now let's check the identifier,
好了,现在让我们检查标识符,
One thing about the identifier is someone might have
一件事的标识符是可能的人
forgotten to set it in the storyboard,
忘记把它在故事板中,
So I'm gonna do an if let on it,
所以我要做一个如果让,
if let identifier = segue,identifier,
如果让标识符= segue,标识符,
Cuz this segue,identifier right here,
因为这个segue,标识符,
you can see is an optional string,
你可以看到是一个可选的字符串,
So it might be not set, in the storyboard,
所以可能没有设置,在故事板中,
So I'm checking to make sure that it is in fact set,
所以我检查以确保它实际上是集,
And now I need the expression, the facial expression,
现在我需要表达,面部表情,
that I'm gonna set in this space for,
我要在这个空间,
this is where I'm gonna do the actual preparing,
这就是我要做实际的准备,
And I could do a little switch, or an if then, else,
我可以做一个小开关,或者一个如果,别的,
if then, else here on all the different segues: sad,
如果其他然后,在所有不同的segue:难过的时候,
happy, worried,
快乐,担心,
But I'm imagining that " my app might have 20 or
但我认为“我的应用程序可能有20或
30 emotions someday",
有一天30情感”,
As such, I wanted to do something a little more
因此,我想做一点事情
extensible, similar to what we did with the calculator brains
可扩展的,类似于我们所做的计算器的大脑
operation, which is I'm going to create a private
操作,我要创建一个私有的
little dictionary here called Emotional Faces,
小字典称为情绪的脸,
And it's going to a dictionary that has Strings as the keys,
和一本字典的字符串键,
and Facial Expressions Facial expressions, FacialExpression,
和面部表情的面部表情,FacialExpression
Oops, sorry this was supposed to be colon
哦,对不起,这是应该是结肠
FacialExpression as the values,
FacialExpression值,
I'm even gonna just put the values in right here,
我甚至会把这里的值,
So this is just a little dictionary,
所以这只是一个小字典,
This string is gonna be the identifier here
这个字符串是这里的标识符
that comes back, the name of our segue,
回来,我们segue的名字,
And the FacialExpression is gonna be the facial expression
和FacialExpression是面部表情
that I want to use there,
我想要使用,
What's it complaining about here?
在这里抱怨什么?
Cuz I didn't have any in there,
因为我没有在那里,
Yeah, cuz we have nothing in here,
是的,因为我们没有在这里,
So let's put some things in here,
让我们把一些东西放在这里,
Let's do sad,
我们难过的时候,
What's a good facial expression for sad?
悲伤的好面部表情是什么?
Well let's create one,
让我们创建一个,
a facial expression where the eyes are probably
一个面部表情,眼睛是可能
closed eyes, and the mouth is in a frown,
闭上眼睛,嘴巴是皱眉,
That sounds pretty sad all around,
这听起来很悲伤,
And then for happy,
然后对于快乐,
it'd probably be the facial expression with the eyes open
这可能是面部表情的眼睛睁开
and we'll let the mouth in a big smile, of course,
我们会让嘴巴大大的微笑,当然,
And I think that worried,
我认为,担心,
I looked at a few facial expressions,
我看着一些面部表情,
I thought, worried, the best thing that looks like that was
我想,这样担心,最好的
eyes open, and the mouth kind of in a, a little smirk,
睁大眼睛,嘴中,有点得意的笑,
That face, for some reason to me, looks a little worried,
那张脸,因为某些原因对我来说,看起来有点担心,
Now I've got this table,
现在我有这个表,
which I can add more things to over time,
我可以添加更多的东西随着时间的推移,
And all I have to do is make a new segue for it, and
我要做的就是创建一个新segue,和
have the identifier match the string here,
标识符匹配字符串,
Now, I might have an identifier that's not in here,
现在,我可能有一个标识符,不是在这里,
so I'm gonna say if I can let the expression I want equal
所以我想说如果我能让表达我想要平等
My emotionalFace is here, sub the identifier,
我emotionalFace这里,子的标识符,
So I'm looking it up there,
所以我想,
But it might come back nil cuz we know that if we
但它可能nil因为我们知道如果我们回来
look something up in dictionary it's not there,
看起来在字典它不在那里,
it will come back nil,
它将返回nil,
So that time we're doing if let,
所以这段时间我们做,如果让
By the way, look at this I have, if let this,
顺便说一下,看看这个,如果让这个,
if let that, if let this,
如果让,如果让这个,
And you can imagine to having four or five of these, and
你可以想象有4或5,和
you start getting really deep, and
你开始真正深,
the code is really kinda messy,
代码是真的有点乱,
You can actually just do these with commas,
你可以只做这些用逗号,
You can just put right here, this one, and then a comma,
你可以把在这里,这一个,然后一个逗号,
and then this one, and then a comma,
这一个,然后一个逗号,
So you can put as many of these things as you want,
所以你可以把你想要尽可能多的这些事情,
And not just lets, you know, if let comma, let comma, but
而不只是让你知道,如果让逗号,逗号,但是
also other expressions too, other things,
还其他的表情,其他的事情,
Like, it's almost like an ampersand kind of expression,
就像,就像一种&的表达式,
And then makes it so
然后让它如此
that I don't need all these curly braces,
我不需要这些花括号,
I can just use this one top level curly brace,
我可以使用这个顶级花括号,
Now I have the expression,
现在我有表达,
Here is where I'm gonna do the prepare,
在这里,我要做准备,
I'm gonna say FaceViewController,
我要FaceViewController说,
prepare yourself by making your model,
自己做好准备,使您的模型,
the expression equal this expression
表达这个表达式相等
that I just looked up in that table,
我刚才抬头一看表,
So that's the actual prepare,
这是实际的准备,
That is where I am preparing this new MVC that it
这就是我准备这新的MVC
created, this brand new FaceViewController I just
新FaceViewController我创建这个品牌
created with the segue,
创建segue,
I'm preparing it to do what it does,
我准备去做它,
So let's see if that works,
让我们看看效果如何,
The face should be prepared now,
面对现在应该做好准备,
When it gets created, we should see a face,
它被创建的时候,我们应该看到一个脸,
The right face,
正确的脸,
Okay, so here it is,
在这里,
Let's try,
让我们试试,
Woo-hoo, happy,
啊,快乐,
Well, it looks a little worried, and sad,
它看起来有点担心,难过的时候,
Now, let's see how happy we are, though, on an iPhone,
现在,让我们看看我们是快乐,不过,在iPhone上,
Because we know that on an iPhone, it's kinda small,
因为我们知道,在iPhone上,有点小,
Split View, not really enough room for a Split View,
拆分视图,没有足够的空间分割视图,
So what's gonna happen with this storyboard on an iPhone?
所以会发生什么故事板在iPhone上吗?
Let's find out,
让我们找到答案,
Okay, well, here we go, Sad, Happy, Worried,
好的,让我们开始,悲伤,快乐,担心,
Excellent, let's see Happy,
好,让我们看看快乐,
All right, we're happy,
好吧,我们很高兴,
Well, now we're not so
好吧,现在我们不是这样的
happy because we can't get out of here,
高兴,因为我们不能离开这里,
We got this happy face but I can't get it back,
我们得到这个笑脸但是我不能把它弄回来,
Let's try going, well, even in landscape, no Split View, so
让我们试试,好吧,即使在景观,没有拆分视图,所以
now there's no way to get back to pick any other expression,
现在没有办法回到选择其他表达式,
So in the iPhone, you get to pick one expression and
在iPhone中,你可以选择一个表达式
you're done, and that's the end of the app,
你完成,结束的应用,
You have to quit the app now because, or
你现在不得不退出应用程序,因为,或
turn your phone off, I guess,
关掉你的手机,我想,
There's absolutely nothing you can do,
绝对没有什么可以做的,
You're stuck, I guess you can make
你卡住了,我猜你可以
the eyes blink,
眼睛闪烁,
So this is not a very good app on the iPhone, obviously,
所以这不是一个很好的应用程序在iPhone上,显然,
That's about it,
这是,
So what are we gonna do?
所以我们要做些什么呢?
Since we have no Split View on the iPhone,
因为我们没有在iPhone上拆分视图,
(you actually can have a Split View on the iPhone by the way,
(你可以有一个拆分视图在iPhone上,
but you have to do a special stuff to kinda enable it,
但是你必须做一个特别的东西有点启用它,
But by default the Split View doesn't work,
但是默认情况下拆分视图不起作用,
Well, of course, Apple understands that,
当然,苹果公司明白,
That Split View is not very good for iPhones,
iphone拆分视图不是很好,
iPhone Plus is by the way, it does work, and
iPhone +顺便说一下,它在工作,
I'm gonna show you that in a moment,
我要告诉你,在一个时刻,
They know it's not that good,
他们不知道它是好,
So if you go back to your storyboard here,
如果你回到你的故事板,
We're gonna go back to our storyboard,
我们将回到我们的故事板,
and we're gonna look at this,
我们要看看这个,
And we're gonna say, hmm, well, on iPhone,
我们会说,嗯,嗯,在iPhone上,
I'd really like this UI to be navigation controller instead,
我真的喜欢这个UI导航控制器相反,
not a Split View,
不是一个拆分视图,
Navigation Controller where when I click on this emotion
导航控制器,当我点击这个情绪
it chose the face by sliding it on top, but
它选择了脸滑,但是
I'll have a back button so
我要一个后退按钮
I can go back, pick a different one,
我可以回去,选择一个不同的一个,
It'll slide it on top and I can hit back,
它会滑上我可以反击,
you see what I mean, so I can go back and forth,
你明白我的意思,所以我可以来回,
And you can do that incredibly simply,
你可以做,非常简单,
You just pick this view control right here, and
你选这个视图控制,
go to editor,
去编辑,
Embed in Navigation Controller,
嵌入在导航控制器,
And it's gonna insert a Navigation Controller
,它会插入导航控制器
in the middle there, see that,
在中间,看到,
how I put that Navigation Controller in there,
我如何把导航控制器,
And what's really cool is with the Navigation Controller you
很酷的是导航控制器的你
actually get a little title bar, and you can go straight
实际上有点标题栏,你可以直走
here in interface builder if you want and
如果你想要在界面构建器
put a title in there like maybe emotions,
把一个标题好像情绪,
We could call it, it's the name of our app or
我们可以叫它,它是我们应用程序的名称
that's what these are in this NVC rather, so
这就是在这个签证中心,而这些都是,
I'll put a little title in there, and that's really cool,
我把一个小标题,很酷,
And so now when we run, I get my face coming up in neutral
现在我们跑的时候,我得到我的脸出现在中性的
mode, and if I go back, now I can pick something like happy,
模式,如果我回去,现在我可以选择快乐之类的东西,
Now one thing you might be interested in there is like,
现在有一件事你可能会感兴趣,
whoa, it came up in neutral mode,
哇,它在中性的模式,
Instead of coming up on this page, you kinda would expected
而不是出现在这个页面中,你会预期
it to come up on this page,, wouldn't you?
在这一页,,不是吗?
And we actually made it extra credit for
我们额外的信用
you to go to figure out how to do it,
你去弄清楚怎么做,
And what you need to
和你需要什么
do is something with Split View Controller,
做是分割视图控制器,
It's delegate, which I'm not gonna talk about the delegates
这是委托,我不会谈论代表
until Wednesday, that's why we made it extra credit,
直到周三,这就是为什么我们额外的信贷,
But you're gonna use Split View's delegate and
但是你要使用视图的委托和分裂
read the documentation, and you can make it so
阅读文档,你可以让它如此
that it'll come up on either page,
它会出现在页面上,
Either on this detailed page or on this master page,
在此详细页面或在这个主页,
But you can see that this is working great, in fact we've
但是你可以看到这是伟大的工作,事实上我们
even got this nice little title bar up here, and we can
甚至有一个漂亮的小标题栏,我们可以
switch back and forth between any emotions that we want,
之间来回切换任何我们想要的情绪,
And let's go see what happened when we did that to iPad,
让我们去看看发生了什么当我们iPad时,
Did we break the iPad?
我们把iPad吗?
Let's hope we didn't break the iPad by doing that,
让我们希望我们没有打破iPad这样做,
Here we go,
我们开始吧,
It comes up,
它出现,
There's the face,
的脸,
By the way, you can do Split Views in Portrait,
顺便说一下,你可以把视图在肖像,
You just slide out,
你只是滑出,
You see, it slides out like a little shelf like that,
你看,它像一个小架子上滑出像,
Or you can rotate and see them side by side,
或者你可以旋转和看到他们肩并肩,
And it's still working,
它仍然是工作,
So the iPad is working just fine,
iPad是工作很好,
Well, unfortunately,
嗯,不幸的是,
there's no zoom level that's a better zoom level,
没有一个更好的缩放级别的缩放级别,
But the iPad has a title here,
但iPad有标题,
But it'd be really cool if there was
但如果有应该会很酷
a title over here, too,
一个标题在这里,
Like maybe this would say, sad and
这也许会说,悲伤和
if I hit happy it would say, happy over here,
如果我点击它会说快乐,快乐在这里,
Wouldn't that be cool?
不会很酷吗?
To have a title on both sides of that, that's
双方有一个标题,这是
often in a Split View that we want, because you want kind of
通常在一个分割视图,我们想要的,因为你想要的
the balance between the two to have tittle on both sides,
两者之间的平衡双方的名字,
So no problem, let's just go back to our storyboard here,
所以没有问题,让我们回到我们的故事板,
and select this View Controller and
并选择这个视图控制器
embed it in a Navigation Controller,
嵌入在导航控制器,
And in fact, if we go here and look at an iPad,
事实上,如果我们去这里看看iPad,
What it's gonna look like on iPad, especially in landscape?
它会是什么样子在iPad上,特别是在景观?
We'll see that,
我们将会看到,
ooh, this is looking what like exactly what we want,
哦,这看起来像什么我们想要什么,
when it's in detail, its got a title bar, a title bar here,
的时候,它有一个标题栏,标题栏,
Look, See,
看,看,
title bars everywhere,
标题栏,
It's fantastic, this is gonna be great,
这将是伟大的,它太棒了
Let's do it,
让我们做它,
All right, look at that, title bar on the top,
好吧,看,标题栏在顶部,
And, uh-oh, we broke it,
哦,我们打破了它,
What happened there?
那里发生了什么事?
Why did we break that?
为什么我们打破了吗?
Well, this has to do with the preparation piece,
嗯,这与制备,
And I talked about this in the lecture last time,
我上次讲过的讲座,
Because what prepare is doing is,
因为准备所做的是,
it's creating a new MVC here, and then we're preparing it,
这里创建一个新的MVC,然后我们准备它,
The problem is that now when it creates a new MVC here,
现在的问题是,当创建一个新的MVC,
what is the MVC?
MVC是什么?
What kind of MVC is it?
什么样的MVC是吗?
Anyone want to hazard a guess?
谁想猜吗?
Cuz it's not a face view controller
因为它不是一个视图控制器
anymore, what is it?
了,这是什么?
Yeah, it's a UI navigation controller,
是的,这是一个UI导航控制器,
That's the new MVC we're creating,
我们创建的新的MVC,
it has a faceView in it, but
它有一个faceView,但是
it's still a UI navigation controller,
这仍然是一个UI导航控制器,
So our code that we have back here,
所以我们的代码,我们回到这里,
That's doing this prepare,
这样做准备,
It says, if I can let the faceView
它说,如果我能让faceView
equal the destination as a FaceViewController,
等于FaceViewController目的地,
Well, I can't do that because it's not,
好吧,我不能这样做,因为它不是,
It's a UI navigation controller instead,
这是一个UI导航控制器相反,
And I'll show you that in debugging here,
我将向您展示,在调试,
Let's go ahead and set a break point right here, and
让我们继续,设置一个断点,和
go back over here and pick one, like happy,
回到这里,选一个,就像快乐,
Here it breaks,
在这里休息,
And if we look at this DestinationViewController,
如果我们看看这个DestinationViewController,
those of you who came to the debugging Friday section,
周五的人来调试部分,
We didn't really go over this cool feature, but
我们没有超过这个很酷的功能,但是
if you just mouse over a variable,
如果你只是鼠标一个变量,
You see how I just,
你看到我,
I'm holding my mouse over DestinationViewController?
我拿着我的鼠标DestinationViewController吗?
You see it's showing that there?
你看到它的显示吗?
There's two really cool buttons in there,
有两个很酷的按钮,
You see this one looks like an i?
你看到这个看起来像一个我吗?
And this one looks like the letter i for info,
这个看起来像这封信我信息,
If you click the one that looks like a i, it'll actually
如果你点击一个看起来像我,它会
show you that View Controller right there in the debugger,
告诉你这视图控制器的调试器,
Which is kinda cool,
这是有点酷,
And if you go over here and click the other little i,
如果你到这里,然后点击另一个我,
it'll show you the class that it is,
它将向您展示的类,
In this case, it's a UI navigation controller,
在这种情况下,它是一个UI导航控制器,
And this works for all kinds of types,
这适用于所有类型的类型,
colors, even a map location,
颜色,甚至地图位置,
It'll show you a map with the location on there,
它将向您展示的地图位置,
So this little mouseover debugging thing is
这小鼠标经过调试的事情
But anyway, we see that DestinationViewController
但无论如何,我们看到DestinationViewController
really cool,
很酷,
right there is a UI navigation controller,
这里是一个UI导航控制器,
We know that's no good,
我们知道没有好,
So what are we gonna do about this?
所以我们要做什么呢?
Well, I'm gonna check for this case, okay?
好了,我要检查这种情况下,好吗?
I'm gonna say, if I can let navigationController equal
我想说,如果我可以让导航控制器相等
the destinationViewController as a UINavigationController,
destinationViewController UINavigationController,
in other words,
换句话说,
if that destination is a UI Navigation Controller, then
如果目的地是UI导航控制器,那么
I'm gonna grab the visible ViewController out of it and
我要抓住它,可见ViewController
use that as the FaceViewController hopefully,
使用,随着FaceViewController希望
So, I'm gonna say in this case I want
所以,我想说在这种情况下我想要的
the destinationViewController, which is this thing up here,
destinationViewController,这个东西,
which now it needs to be a var and so
现在需要一个var和
I'm gonna change its value here,
我要改变它的值,
I'm gonna let that equal,
我要让这相同的情况下,
the navigationController's visibleViewController,
导航控制器的visibleViewController,
Okay, now this is great,
好了,现在这是伟大的,
visibleViewController is a really nice method and
visibleViewController是一个很好的方法
navigation control, it shows you whichever
导航控制,它显示了哪个
card stack is currently visible, exactly what I want,
卡堆栈目前可见的,正是我想要的,
The only problem with it, however, is it returns
然而,唯一的问题是它的回报
an optional, because nothing might be visible in
一个可选的,因为不可能是可见的
the navigationController right now,
现在导航控制器,
Okay, you might have never put anything
好吧,你可能从来没有把任何东西
in the navigationController,
在导航控制器,
So since that is an optional, I'm gonna have to give it
既然这是一个可选的,我必须给它
some default value, and the default value,
一些默认值,默认值,
I'm just gonna say, just use the destinationViewController
我只是想说,只使用destinationViewController
as is if I can't get the visible ViewController or
就像如果我不能得到ViewController或可见
the navigationController,
导航控制器,
So it's kinda a default to use what it already was,
所以它有点默认使用它已经是什么,
Basically, don't change it,
基本上,不改变它,
So this little if is nice, because now my code works if
所以这个小如果是好的,因为现在我的代码是否工作
it's in a navigationController or even if it's not,
在导航控制器,甚至如果不是,
Because if it's not in a navigationController,
因为如果它不是在导航控制器,
this is gonna do nothing,
这是要做什么,
That's going to fail,
的失败,
Alright, this as is not going to work,
好了,这是不会工作,
And we'll go straight down to checking
我们会直接去检查
if it's a FaceViewControllor,
如果是FaceViewControllor,
So if I later came along back to my storyboard here and
所以如果我后来回到我的故事板在这里
eh, you know what, I don't really want the title on here,
嗯,你知道,我真的不希望标题在这里,
I decided,
我决定,
And I took this navigationController out
我把这个导航控制器
of the picture, my code would still work, cuz my code works
的图片,我的代码仍然会工作,因为我的代码工作
whether I'm going straight to a FaceController or
是否我直接FaceController或
through a navigationController,
通过导航控制器,
Let's see if that indeed fixed our problem,
让我们看看确实固定问题,
Here we go, let's try it,
我们开始吧,让我们试试。
Happy, yeah, worried, sad,
快乐,是的,担心,难过的时候,
Happy, we're happy that it's working,
快乐,我们快乐的工作,
Okay, now we have this nice title bar at the top and
好的,现在我们有一个好的标题栏在顶部
we said, wouldn't it be cool if we could put a title, so
我们说,岂不是很酷,如果我们可以把一个标题,所以
let's do that,
让我们这样做,
Let's put a little title here,
让我们把一个小标题,
in fact the title I'm gonna put here is whichever button
事实上这里的标题我将是哪个按钮
brought this MVC up,
把这个MVC,
So if the sad button brought it up,
如果悲伤的按钮了,
I'm gonna get its current title and put it up here,
我要得到当前标题和把它放在这里,
kinda like we did in the calculator,
有点像我们的计算器,
Look back to the sender and luckily prepare for segue,
回顾发送方和幸运的是准备继续,
has the sender,
发送者,
This is the thing that cause the segue to happen,
这是导致segue的事情发生,
Which is going to be one of those buttons,
这是其中的一个按钮,
So right down here, I can just get the current title of this
所以在这里,我可以得到当前标题
sender right here and set that to be the title,
发送者和设置标题,
Now if you remember from the lecture about
现在如果你还记得讲
navigationController, the way that you
导航控制器的方法
set things that appear when it's in a navigationController
设置当它出现在导航控制器的事情
like the title, you can also set the buttons,
如标题,您还可以设置按钮,
the back button title you can set,
后退按钮标题可以设置,
or you can even put write buttons in the top,
或者你甚至可以把写按钮在顶部,
You do that with this thing called NavigationItem on
你用这个东西做,名为NavigationItem
UIViewController,
ui,
So I'm gonna take the faceViewController's
所以我要把faceViewController的
navigationItem, which, by the way the navigationItem,
navigationItem navigationItem,顺便说一下,
you can just kind of think of it as
你可以认为它是
a bag of goodies that only UINavigationController uses,
一袋糖果,只有UINavigationController使用,
And it only looks in that bag of goodies
,它只是看起来袋糖果
when this ViewController, the faceViewController,
当这个ViewController、faceViewController
is the visible ViewController in the NavigationController,
可见ViewController的导航控制器,
Then it looks in this bag of goodies and you can see that
然后在这个袋子看起来好吃的东西,你可以看到
there's a lot of things in the bag of goodies,
有很多事情在袋糖果,
like leftBarButtonItem, rightBarButtonItems, and
像leftBarButtonItem,rightBarButtonItems,
of course the title,
当然,标题,
Which is what I want to set here,
我在这里想要设置的,
I want to set the title of the navigationController
我想设置导航控制器的标题
when this thing is visible,
当这个东西是可见的,
And I'm gonna send it,
我将发送它,
I want to send it to the sender's current title, but
我想寄给发送方目前的头衔,但是
I can't quite do that,
我不能完全做到这一点,
Why can't I do that?
我为什么不能这样做呢?
Why is that not gonna work?
为什么不工作?
This,
这一点,
See any problem?
看到任何问题吗?
Yeah, this is Any,
是的,这是任何,
And Any does not understand any messages,
任何不理解的任何消息,
Because it doesn't know what it is,
因为它不知道它是什么,
So we have to take this any and turn it into a UI button,
所以我们必须把这和把它变成一个UI按钮,
And we do that by saying this, sender as the UIButton,
我们说这个,UIButton发送者,
Now we could almost send current title,
现在我们几乎可以把标题,
The only problem is this,
唯一的问题是,
What is this type of,
这是什么类型的,
what is the type of, if I can select it, this expression?
是什么类型的,如果我可以选择,这个表达式?
What's its type?
它的类型是什么?
No one wanna guess on this one?
没有人想猜吗?
No one?
没有人吗?
It's an optional, right?
这是一个可选的,对吧?
Because "as?" returns an optional, so this is
因为“?
an optional, so we can't send an optional current title,
一个可选的,所以我们不能发送一个可选的当前标题,
We need to either exclamation point it, or
我们需要感叹号,或
a little safer, we could optional chain it,
安全,我们可以选链,
Because we know that optional chaining is just going to
因为我们知道,可选的链接就是
ignore the rest of this expression if that happened to
忽略这个表达式如果发生
not be a button,
不是一个按钮,
And this as returned nil,
这是返回nil,
because this couldn't be turned into a button,
因为这不能变成一个按钮,
So we'll just optional chain in which case the title here
所以我们就选链在这种情况下,这里的标题
will be set to nil, because this whole thing will be nil
将被设置为零,因为这整件事会nil
if this optional chaining doesn't happen,
如果这个可选的链接不会发生,
And that's okay,
这是好的,
because we look at the title of a navigation item,
因为我们看导航项的标题,
It's an optional,
这是一个可选的,
So we can send it to a nil,
所以我们可以把这个表寄给一个零,
And then this will, it will have no title up there,
然后这将,它将没有标题,
I intentionally put this thing in here for
我故意把这事在这里
lot of things going on here,
很多事情,
We have the any cast going on,
我们有任何铸造,
We have optional chaining going on here,
我们有可选的链接,
We use the navigation item,
我们使用的导航项,
So there is a lot in this line of code,
所以有很多在这行代码,
So make sure you kind of understand what's
所以确保你明白的
all the pieces going on there,
所有的碎片,
Now we should be getting hopefully the title of
现在我们应该得到希望的标题
the button appearing as the title on the right-hand side,
按钮的标题出现在右手边,
So happy, sure enough, there's happy,
所以快乐,果然,有快乐,
Worried, there's worried,
担心,担心,
Sad, happy,
悲伤,快乐,
And of course if we rotate,
当然如果我们旋转,
we're still getting the title up there,
我们还得到了冠军,
We can slide this thing out and pick sad,
这个东西我们可以滑出,选择悲伤,
and it happens back there,
和它发生,
Slide that thing out of the way if we want,
幻灯片的事情的,如果我们想要的,
Rotate back,
旋转,
How about iPhone 7?
iPhone 7呢?
Let's see if we've
我们来看看我们
broken that,
坏了,
It appears with this split views detail coming up first
似乎与此分割视图细节上来
in this neutral mode,
在这个中立的模式,
We'll go back to emotions,
我们将回到情绪,
Pick Happy,
选择快乐,
Sure enough, it's setting that title fine there as well,
果然,那里设置标题好,
If we go here,
如果我们去这里,
Since it's an iPhone, can't do split view,
因为它是iPhone,不能拆分视图,
it's still working fine in navigationController mode,
它仍然是在导航控制器模式下工作正常,
Let's go look at a 7 Plus,
让我们去看一个7 +,
There is a 7 plus which is kind of a high breed
有一个7 +的高繁殖
between iPhone 7 and an iPad,
7 iPhone和iPad之间,
And in portrait mode,
在竖屏模式,
an iPhone 7 plus works just like an iPhone,
iPhone 7 +作品就像iPhone一样,
So it's gonna be the
所以它会
navigationController back and forth,
来回导航控制器,
But in landscape, it'll work like an iPad,
但在景观,它会工作像iPad一样,
Okay, so obviously an iPhone 7 plus in portrait mode,
好吧,显然iPhone 7 +在肖像模式下,
it is not big enough to do the slide-out thing like an iPad
它不够大做滑盖的事情像iPad
does in portrait mode, but in landscape mode it is, so
在竖屏模式,但在横向模式,所以呢
let's make it so this thing fits,
让我们让这个东西,
That's close enough to fitting,
这是足够接近,
I'll go small here,
我要小,
All right, so this is a plus,
好吧,这是一个+,
And you can see it comes up in portrait mode,
你可以看到它出现在肖像模式下,
It's acting like it's an iPhone,
它像一个iPhone,
See that, okay?
看到,好吗?
It's just doing that,
只是这样做,
But look what happens if I go to landscape mode,
但是如果我去看看发生了什么风景模式,
I get a split view,
我得到一个拆分视图,
Tha's working fine,
那工作很好,
So see how we built in the storyboard this hybrid UI and
我们看到建在这个混合UI和故事板
it works on all the different kinds of devices,
它适用于所有不同种类的设备,
No matter whether they control with you or
无论他们对你或控制
not it'll default go back to using
没有它会默认使用
navigationController, whatever,
导航控制器等等,
And the only thing we had to do in our code
和我们要做的唯一的事在我们的代码
as a concession to the cross-platform is checking for
作为一个跨平台的让步是检查
that navigationController and only for
导航控制器和只
the thing we were segueing to,
我们segue,
Back to the slides,
幻灯片,
Our next topic here is the View Controller Lifecycle,
我们下一个主题是视图控制器生命周期,
Now, everything has a life cycle,
现在,每件事都有一个生命周期,
even we have a life cycle: we're born, we live our lives,
即使我们有一个生命周期:我们出生时,我们的生活,
things happen, and we die,
事情发生,我们死了,
Well, that happens to a View Controller as well,
这发生在一个视图控制器,
It's just born, things happen to it, and then it dies,
它只是出生,事情发生,然后它死了,
it leaves the heap,
它的叶子堆,
That's what happens on its death,
这就是发生在其死后,
Why do we care about the view controller lifecycle?
为什么我们关心视图控制器的生命周期?
Because we often wanna do things at various key
因为我们经常要做的事情在不同的关键
inflection points in its lifetime,
拐点在它的生命周期,
The start of a lifecycle is really simple,
生命周期的开始是很简单的,
It gets initialized, and 99,99% of
它被初始化,到99年,99%的
the time a view controller is coming out of a storyboard,
一个视图控制器的故事板,
Its initializer is this special initializer coming out
其初始化这个特殊的初始化出来
of a storyboard,
故事板,
In your reading assignments,
在你阅读作业,
I actually explained how this works,
我解释说这是如何工作的,
But we don't usually override the initializer of a view
但是我们通常不会覆盖一个视图的初始值设定项
We're going to use the other ways we know to initialize
我们要用我们所知道的其他方法来初始化
controller,
控制器,
each variables,
每一个变量,
I'm not even gonna talk about how to make one in code,
我甚至不讲如何使一个代码,
Because we just, just don't do that,
因为我们只是,只是不要这样做,
You can see why, right?
你可以看到为什么,对吧?
Because view controller is complicated,
因为视图控制器是复杂的,
It's got all the UI, the buttons, and all the stuff,
它有所有UI,按钮,和所有的东西,
You're generally not gonna be making that in code,
你通常不会做,在代码中,
What happens then after it's created?
之后它创建的时候会发生什么?
The next thing that happens is if it's being segued to,
接下来发生的是,如果它被马上决定,
it gets prepared,
就准备好了,
Like when we prepared the FaceView Controller there by
当我们准备FaceView控制器
setting it to model,
设置模型,
That's the next thing that happens after it's
这就是接下来要发生的事情之后
initialized,
初始化,
The next thing that happens is its outlets get set,
接下来发生的事情是它的网点设置,
So, for the FaceView,
因此,对于FaceView,
its FaceView outlet got set after it got prepared,
其FaceView出口设置了准备后,
Then, it appears and disappears on screen,
然后,似乎消失在屏幕上,
In our example right there, the master
在我们的示例中,主人
was constantly appearing and disappearing on screen,
不停地出现和消失在屏幕上,
Every time, on the iPhone, for example, that we hit happy or
每次,在iPhone上,例如,我们快乐或
sad, it would disappear,
难过的时候,它会消失,
And the face one would come on,
面对一个会,
And then, we'd hit back and it would reappear,
然后,我们会反击,它会出现,
By the way, when that happens, the face one didn't disappear,
顺便说一下,当这种情况发生时,面对一个没有消失,
Well, it disappeared and
它消失了,
it also got thrown out of the heap,
它也有堆的扔掉,
Because we reuse the things we segue to,
因为我们重用我们继续,
But that master, we don't segue to it,
但是,主人,我们不继续,
It sits there as the master in the split view all the time,
它的主人坐在那儿拆分视图,
But it's appearing and disappearing on screen,
但它的出现和消失在屏幕上,
So that's a big thing that happens its lifecycle,
这是一件大事发生它的生命周期,
Another thing that happens
另一件事发生了
during the life time of it is it's changing its orientation,
在它的生命时间的改变方向,
We're rotating the landscape,
我们旋转的风景,
We're on a iPad and
我们在iPad和
we're sliding it out as a tray in portrait mode and
我们滑出来在肖像模式和一个托盘
then we rotate to landscape and it's sitting on the side,
然后我们旋转到景观坐在一边,
So it's changing its shape,
这是改变其形状,
Even the face view of the iPad when we're in portrait,
即使面对的iPad在肖像,
it's big, tall and big,
它很大,又高又大,
But then we switch to landscape it's kind of more
但是我们切换到景观的更多
like a square, and a little smaller,
像一个广场,有点小,
So it's always changing geometry,
所以它总是变化的几何,
And then it could be in a low memory situation as well where
然后它也可能在低内存的情况下
we need to recovery some memory,
我们需要恢复一些内存,
this almost never happens, but I have to mention it,
这几乎从来没有发生,但我不得不提到它,
It's really maybe not even part of the view controller
很可能没有视图控制器的一部分
lifecycle but it's a good place to talk about it,
生命周期,但这是一个好地方谈论它,
cuz it's not really that important,
因为它并不是真的那么重要,
Let's talk about the messages that
让我们来谈谈的消息
are sent to invoke methods in your view controller
被发送到调用方法在你的视图控制器吗
when these various things happen,
当这些不同的事情发生,
So you already know about your outlets being set,
所以你已经知道你的网点设置,
And you can watch that with your did sets,
你可以看,与你的并集,
the property observer, did set,
财产的观察者,集,
And you already know about preparing,
和你已经知道的准备,
I just showed you about that,
我刚给你们看,
So after those two steps are done,
所以这两个步骤完成后,
you're gonna get this message, viewDidLoad,
你会得到这条消息,viewDidLoad,
Super important method,
非常重要的方法,
You're only gonna ever receive it once in the lifetime
你永远只会收到一次一生
of a viewController,
viewController的
And it's really where you're gonna put
这是真的,你要把
almost all of your initialization,
几乎所有的初始化,
For example, a lot of times here's where you'll call your
例如,很多时候你会打电话给你
update UI method, the thing that updates your UI from your
更新用户界面方法,更新的东西从你的UI
model, very often you're gonna call that in viewDidLoad,
模型,通常你会叫viewDidLoad,
Cuz now your model is set because it got prepared
因为现在你的模型集,因为它有准备
probably, and your outlets are set because this is how it
可能,你的网点设置,因为这是它
always happens after outlet setting,
总是发生出口设置后,
Now, one thing not to do in here though,
现在,在这里不做的一件事,
Very careful, listen carefully,
非常小心,仔细听,
Do not do geometry-based things in viewDidLoad,
不做几何viewDidLoad,
Because when viewDidLoad happens,
因为当viewDidLoad发生,
you have not yet had your final geometry established,
你还没有最终建立几何,
You don't quite know if you're portrait, landscape,
你不知道如果你的肖像,风景,
what device you're on, you don't know yet,
什么设备,你还不知道,
So do not do things with your bounds in viewDidLoad,
所以不要做的事情与你在viewDidLoad界限,
Many of you will make this mistake so perk up those ears,
你们中的很多人将这个错误所以活跃起来的耳朵,
Do not do that,
不这样做,
I'm gonna show you other methods in the new controller
我会给你其他方法在新的控制器
lifecycle for doing that but do not it in viewDidLoad,
生命周期进行,但不要viewDidLoad,
The next thing I said to you, appear and disappearing,
接下来我对你说,出现和消失,
You're always appearing and disappearing on screen,
你总是出现和消失在屏幕上,
When you appear, you're gonna get two messages,
当你出现时,你会得到两个消息,
The first is viewWillAppear,
首先是那些,
And that's sent to you before you're actually on screen, but
这是寄给你之前你实际上在屏幕上,但是
just very very soon going to be,
非常很快,
guaranteed you're going to be on screen soon,
保证你很快就会在屏幕上,
So, what is viewWillAppear for?
那么,那些是什么?
What are you going to do in a view will appear?
你打算做什么在视图将出现?
Well one thing is if there's anything that changes in your
有一件事是如果有任何的改变
model when you're not on screen,
当你没有在屏幕上,模型
maybe your model is a network database or
也许你的模型是一个数据库或网络
something and it's changing on the screen,
在屏幕上的改变,
Then when view appear happens you're going to usually update
当视图出现发生你会经常更新
your UI from your model,
UI从你的模型,
So maybe you wouldn't do update UI in viewDidLoad,
也许你不会在viewDidLoad做更新UI,
you might do it here,
你可以在这里,
That's if it could change when it's not onscreen,
如果它能改变当不是在屏幕上,
A lot of MVCs,
很多mvc,
their model only changes when they're onscreen, so
他们的模型只改变当他们在屏幕上,所以
you wouldn't have to do anything here,
你不需要做任何事情,
But if your model can be changed out from under you
但是,如果您的模型可以改变下你
while you're off screen, then you, when you reappear,
当你关闭屏幕,然后,当你再次出现,
obviously you wanna show the current state of your model,
显然你想显示的当前状态模型,
So that's a good one,
这是一个好的,
Another thing you might do in viewWillAppear
你可能做的另一件事进行处理
is start something expensive,
开始是昂贵的,
Because in viewDidLoad you're not guaranteed that you're
因为在viewDidLoad你不能保证
ever gonna come on screen,
会出现在屏幕上,
There are MVCs that occasionally get loaded up,
有mvc偶尔会加载,
but then the user clicks away somewhere else and
然后用户点击其他地方和
you never get shown on screen,
你永远不显示在屏幕上,
But if viewWillAppear happens,
但是如果那些发生,
you know you're going on screen,
你知道你会在屏幕上,
So here you could kick off something expensive,
这里你可以启动一些昂贵的,
Especially kick off a thread that goes and
特别是和启动一个线程
does something expensive in the background,
在后台做了一些昂贵的,
Cuz we're gonna talk about multithreading next week and
因为我们下周要讨论多线程
you're gonna see that anything that takes any amount of time
你会发现,任何的时间
or energy on the part of the processor or the network,
或能量的处理器或网络,
you're gonna wind up doing a separate thread,
你要做一个单独的线程,
So you might kick off such a thread here in viewWillAppear,
所以你可能会启动一个线程进行处理,
There's also an another method,
还有另一种方法,
viewDidAppear which gets into after you're fully on screen,
viewDidAppear进入后你完全在屏幕上,
The animation to get you on screen is on screen so
让你在屏幕上的动画是在屏幕上
you're there,
你在那里,
And what would you do here?
你会做什么呢?
There's usually not a lot to do here,
这里通常没有很多事情要做,
You might start an animation though,
你可能会开始一个动画,
You've got some MVC that has some animation going,
你有一些MVC,动画,
And it doesn't make any sense to start it before it
它没有任何意义开始之前
So once it gets on screen then you start it going,
所以一旦在屏幕上然后你开始,
gets on screen,
在屏幕上,
ViewWillAppear and viewDidAppear happen so
那些和viewDidAppear发生
close together, it's probably not gonna save much to wait
近,它可能不会节省太多等
until viewDidAppear to start the animation,
直到viewDidAppear开始动画,
but eh, a lot of people will do that,
但是呃,很多人会这样做,
just to kind of for clarity of programming,
为了清晰的编程,
And then, of course,
然后,当然,
you can disappear, and get the same thing there,
你可以消失,得到同样的事情,
a viewWillDisappear and a viewDidDisappear,
viewWillDisappear和viewDidDisappear,
One thing you notice in all of these view controller
你注意到在所有这些视图控制器
lifecycle is that I'm calling super,
生命周期是我打电话超,
You see that?
你看到了吗?
super,viewWillDisappear, and I did it for
超级viewWillDisappear,我做到了
superViewDidLoad, and superViewWillAppear,
superViewDidLoad superViewWillAppear,
All of them, all of the view controller lifecycle methods,
所有这些,所有的视图控制器生命周期方法,
always call super,
总是叫超,
You always wanna give your super class chance to do it,
你总是想给你超类的机会,
You'll see actually in the demo why you do that,
你会看到实际的演示你为什么这样做,
Always do that,
总是这样做,
Always do super there,
总是做超级存在,
So in viewWillDisappear, a lot of times here you're
所以在viewWillDisappear,很多时候你在这里
undoing the things you did in viewDidAppear,
取消你在viewDidAppear,
Like if you had an animation going,
如果你有一个动画,
you're gonna stop it here,
你会停止在这里,
because you're about to disappear,
因为你要消失了,
Here you might also start some cleanup,
在这里你也可以开始一些清理,
Your MVC disappeared, and
你的MVC消失了,
so, if you allocated some resources or something that
所以,如果你一些资源或者分配
you don't need, network connection open or something,
你不需要,网络连接打开,
That only makes sense to be open while your MVC is on,
只有合理开放你的MVC的同时,
then here is a good place where you can shut it down,
这里是一个好地方,你可以关闭它,
and there is a did version of this as well,
和有一个版本的,
A lot of times people look at viewDidAppear and
很多时候人们看着viewDidAppear和
viewWillDisappear as matched, you know, one undoes
viewWillDisappear匹配,你知道,一个寓言
the other, and then the same thing with viewWillAppear and
,然后和那些同样的事情
viewDidDisappear, those are gonna undo each other,
viewDidDisappear,彼此会撤销,
I still haven't talked about geometry until now,
我还没有谈到几何直到现在,
You don't want to be doing geometry in viewWillAppear,
你不想做几何进行处理,
Your geometry actually probably is set
你的几何实际上可能被设置
in viewWillAppear, but you shouldn't count on that,
进行处理,但你不应该指望,
You shouldn't do geometry in the view wills and
你不应该做遗嘱和几何的视图
did appears and disappears either,
出现和消失,
Geometry changes: there's methods especially for it,
特别是它几何变化:有方法,
One thing to consider is, you almost never need to write any
要考虑的一件事是,你几乎不需要写任何
code when your geometry changes,
代码当你的几何形状的变化,
That's cuz you have auto layout,
因为你有自动布局,
I mean, look at the app I just wrote,
我的意思是,看看我刚写的应用程序,
I've got that sad, happy, worried block of text, and
我有悲伤,快乐,担心的文本块,
when I rotate it it stays in the middle,
当我转动它停留在中间,
I didn't have to write any code for that,
我不需要编写任何代码,
And even more complicated UI's,
甚至更复杂的UI,
You're usually using auto layout and
你通常使用自动布局
it's doing it for you,
为你做它,
So most time you don't need any code,
所以大部分时间你不需要任何代码,
But if you did feel like you needed to do some code
但是如果你觉得你需要做一些代码
Let's talk a little bit about how you do that,
让我们谈谈如何做,
There's two methods, viewWillLayoutSubviews and
有两种方法,viewWillLayoutSubviews和
viewDidLayoutSubviews,
And these are sent to you,
这些是寄给你,
In between these being sent to you, Autolayout happens,
在这些被送到你之间,自动布局,
So if you wanna get involved in the geometry change of your
如果你想要参与的几何变化
view, before Autolayout starts,
看来,在自动布局开始之前,
you can do it in view will layout subviews,
你可以在子视图,视图将布局
If you wanna wait until Autolayout does what it does
如果你想等到自动布局也没有什么
and then you wanna get involved,
然后你想参与,
you can do it in viewDidLayoutSubviews,
你可以在viewDidLayoutSubviews,
So when did these get called?
因此,当这些被调用吗?
When a bounds of a view changes,
当一个视图的变化,
all of its subviews might have to be moved around,
它的所有子视图可能要搬家,
Maybe the view is know tall and
视图可能是知道高大
thin, instead of short and wide,
瘦,短而宽,
It's views are gonna have to be moved to be in the right
它的观点会搬到是正确的
place, just like again we rotated the emotions thing and
的地方,就像我们情绪的事,旋转
we need to move that stack view up or
我们需要移动或堆栈视图
all over a little bit sustained in the middle,
在持续的在中间,一点
That's primarily what's going on here,
主要是这是怎么回事,
that's why this method is called viewWillLayoutSubviews,
这就是为什么viewWillLayoutSubviews调用此方法,
Its bounds changed and
其范围改变,
now all its subviews need to be laid out,
现在它的所有子视图需要,
What about the things the view actually draws itself like
视图实际上画自己喜欢的事情呢
the face?
面对吗?
That has nothing to do with this,
与此无关,
That's a view thing,
这是一个视图,
That face view, when the bounds change, if it's content
那张脸看来,当范围改变,如果它的内容
mode is redraw like we set it for the face view, it's draw
模式是重绘像我们设置它的脸看来,画
method's automatically gonna get called at the new bounds,
方法的自动在新边界会被调用,
So you don't have to do anything there,
所以你不需要做任何事,
So viewWillLayoutSubviews,
所以viewWillLayoutSubviews,
is what happens, when you have subviews,
是发生了什么,当你有子视图,
This happens at the view level, so views have a method
这种情况发生在视图层,所以观点有一个方法
for laying out their subviews, called layoutSubviews,
布置他们的子视图,称为layoutSubviews,
Subviews, and the ViewController also gets to
子视图,视图控制器也可以
find out when its view, and by this I mean the var
找出它的视图时,,我的意思是说,var
view in ViewController, you remember what that var is?
在ViewController视图,你记得,var是什么吗?
That's that top level view,
这是顶级视图,
There's a var for that in your ViewController,
有一个var ViewController中,
it's saying that view is going to layout its subviews, and
这是说视图布局它的子视图,和
that happens when that top level view changes, usually
当顶级视图变化,通常
due to rotation but other things can change it as well,
由于旋转但其他事情可以改变它,
One thing about these methods is you should expect that they
关于这些方法的一件事是你应该相信他们
may be called all the time,
可能被称为,
Don't try to anticipate when they're going to be called,
不要试图预测当他们被称为,
Just, whenever they're called, you do what you're supposed,
只是,每当它们叫做,你做你应该
you're supposed to do,
你应该做的,
and they might be called repeatedly with the same
他们可以被称为反复使用相同的
bounds,
界限,
So the bounds might not actually have changed,
因此可能不会有改变,
because this is not called view bounds changed this is
因为这不是叫视图范围改变了这是
called viewWillLayoutSubviews and viewDidLayoutSubviews,
叫viewWillLayoutSubviews viewDidLayoutSubviews,
And there are other things besides bounds changes that
还有其他事情除了范围变化
might cause that top-level view to have to layout it's
可能导致顶层视图布局的
sub views,
子视图,
So expect this to be called fairly often and
所以希望这个经常被称为
you should always react to it correctly,
你应该正确地反应,
Even if it's called repeatedly with the same
即使它被称为反复使用相同的
bounds or whatever,
界限,
Now, auto rotation,
现在,自动旋转,
the bounds changing by rotating the device, actually
实际上,边界变化的旋转设备
has a couple of little extra pieces of interest to it,
有两个额外的利益,
The most notable is animation,
最著名的是动画,
So normally when you rotate it's just going to be
通常当你旋转它就是
ViewWillLayoutSubviews and everything's just going to,
ViewWillLayoutSubviews,一切都要
auto layout's going to happen, everything is happening fine,
自动布局会发生,一切都发生得很好,
However that changes, all those changes are animated,
然而,变化,这些变化都是动画,
If you look closely when you rotate your device, all
如果你仔细看当你旋转设备
the views are kind of flying across to their new location,
的观点是飞越他们的新位置,
It's really kinda cool actually,
其实真的很酷,
They're being animated,
他们是动画,
They don't just pop appear in the new place,
他们不只是流行出现在新地方,
they slide over,
他们回避,
Well, you can participate in that animation,
嗯,你可以参与动画,
now we haven't talked about animation,
现在我们还没有谈到动画,
We will in about three weeks,
我们将在大约三个星期,
But you can participate with this method,
但是你可以用这种方法,参与
ViewwillTransition to size with coordinator,
ViewwillTransition大小与协调员,
And that coordinator has a little closure you can set on
关闭,协调器有一个小你可以设置
it that will cause some animation you want to do
这将导致一些动画你想做的事
to happen alongside the rotations animation,
发生在旋转动画,
So if you want to animate moving some user doing
所以如果你想动画移动一些用户做的
something else that doesn't happen automatically for you,
东西不会发生自动为你,
which most stuff does with autolayout,
大多数东西与自动布局,
you can do that here with this method,
你可以用这种方法,
Low-memory: didReceiveMemoryWarning
内存:didReceiveMemoryWarning
will be sent to your view controller when
将被送到你的视图控制器什么时候
the system's low on memory, it's trying to get some back,
系统的低内存,它试图得到一些回来,
This almost never happens,
这几乎从未发生,
I just can't remember the last time this happened because
我只是不记得最后一次这个是因为
the devices have so much memory these days,
这些天,设备有这么多内存
Usually if this happens though, you wanna pay
通常如果发生这种情况,你要支付
attention because you're using a lot of memory,
因为你使用了大量的内存,注意
If the system is sending this to you, either you are or
如果系统发送这个给你,或者你
some other app is using a lot of memory,
其他应用程序正在使用大量的内存,
By the way, if you are an app that uses a lot of memory, and
顺便说一下,如果你是一个应用程序,使用大量的内存,和
you don't keep it under control,
你不控制它,
the system has the right to just kill you,
系统有权就杀了你,
Just kill your app,
杀了你的应用程序,
And it will do it, absolutely,
它会这样做,当然,
Even if you're in the background,
即使你的背景,
if you've allocated a ton of memory and you're being a bad
如果你分配大量的内存和你是一个坏的
citizen they just kill you off to get your memory back what
公民就杀你去取回你的记忆
kinda memory would you free up if you got this method,
有些记忆你会释放如果你有这个方法,
Let's say you had an image that's not currently on
假设你有一个图片没有
screen, and you can create it from a file on disk,
屏幕,您可以创建从磁盘上的文件,
We haven't really talked about this, but your phone has
我们还没有讨论过这个问题,但是你的电话
permanent storage, flash memory, and you have,
永久存储、闪存和,
let's say a JPEG image, you can just recreate it,
假设JPEG图像,你可以重新创建它,
Well, you would definitely release that here,
嗯,你一定会在这里释放,
Cuz it's not on-screen, and
因为它不是屏幕上
you can create it real fast from the disk,
你可以从磁盘创建它真正的快,
so there's no reason to keep it around,
所以没有理由保留它,
So that's something you could release,
这是一些你可以释放,
Basically any memory that you can quickly recreate,
基本上任何您可以快速创建的内存,
Or that is not currently on-screen, and
或者这不是当前屏幕,
you can create it when that comes back on-screen,
你可以创建屏幕回来的时候,
That's a good thing to release,
这是一件好事来释放,
But only big things,
但只有大事情,
Don't release little tiny 100 byte things,
不释放小100字节,
No, we're talking images, sounds, videos,
不,我们说的图片,声音,视频,
big ol' things,
大的事情,
There's one other little thing:
还有一个小的事情:
it's not part of the UIcontroller life cycle, but
这不是uicontrol生命周期的一部分,但是
every single object that comes out of a storyboard: views,
每一个对象的一个故事板:视图,
view controllers, everything gets sent awakeFromNib and
视图控制器,一切发送awakeFromNib和
they can send it pretty early,
他们可以很早就发送,
Like right as soon as they come
就像对
out they get sent awake from nib,
他们从笔尖获得发送清醒,
Now you can't use it to like satisfy the requirement that
现在你不能用它来满足要求
all vars are initialized,
var是初始化,
But you can use it do early, really early initialization,
但你可以用它做早,早早初始化,
For example remember I mentioned about you want your
例如记得我提到你希望
split view controller to come up showing the face or
分屏视图控制器来显示或的脸
come up showing the emotions instead of showing the face?
来显示情绪而不是显示的脸?
In your calculator,
在你的计算器,
it would come up showing the calculator,
它会显示计算器,
instead of the calculator's graph, and
而不是计算器的图,
I said you needed to do that by setting the delegate,
我说你需要通过设置委托,
This delegate of the SplitViewController,
SplitViewController这个委托,
that's something you might wanna do to make
这是你可能想做的事
get that delegate involved early,
早期参与委托时,
We'll talk about delegates on Wednesday,
我们将讨论代表周三,
So awake from nib, rarely used and sometimes overused,
所以从笔尖清醒,很少使用,有时过度使用,
I would say if you could put it in another method like view
我想说如果你可以把它放在另一个方法的观点
did load or view will appear or view,
确实会出现或视图或视图加载,
Did layout put it there first,
布局是先把它放在那里,
Don't put it in away fromNib,
不要把它放在fromNib,
that's kind of a last resort place to put things,
这是最后的地方放东西,
It's probably better than overriding in it,
它可能比覆盖,
But that's the only thing it's better than,
但这是唯一比,
So here's the summary of the entire view controller
这是总结整个视图控制器
lifecycle,
生命周期,
You can instantiated, created out of the storyboard,
你可以实例化,创建故事板,
You get awake from nib sent to you,
你醒着的nib寄给你,
Segue prep happens,
Segue预科,
Somebody prepares you if you're being segued to
有人准备你如果你马上决定
which most MVC's are,
大多数MVC,
Outlets get set,
机构设置,
Your face view, and your calculator,
你的脸看,和你的计算器,
It's your display and things like that get set up,
这是你展示之类的设置,
ViewDidLoad gets called,
ViewDidLoad被调用,
Again, with viewDidLoad, look at all the things that
再次,viewDidLoad,看看所有的事情
happened by the time viewDidLoad gets called,
发生viewDidLoad被调用的时候,
It's a great place to put initialization,
这是一个很好的地方来存放初始化,
You enter kind of the normal life cycle
您输入的正常生命周期
where you're getting appearing and disappearing,
你的出现和消失,
disappearing with the the will and did appear and disappears,
消失的,也会出现和消失,
Appearing and
出现和
Along the way, and at any time actually,
一路上,实际上,任何时候
even before viewDidLoad, you can get these sent to,
viewDidLoad之前,你可以把这些送到,
Although that would be rare,
虽然这是罕见的,
But anytime you can be,
但任何时候你可以,
actually I'm not sure you can get it before viewDidLoad,
实际上我不确定你可以得到它在viewDidLoad之前,
Take that back But any time when view will appear and
后退,视图将出现,但任何时候
disappear is happening, whether you're on-screen or
正在消失,不管你是在屏幕上
not, you could get viewWillLayout subviews and
不是,你可以得到viewWillLayout子视图
viewDidLayout subviews sent to you, auto-layout happening,
viewDidLayout子视图发给你,自动布局发生,
By the way, why would you ever be sent these methods
顺便问一下,为什么你发送这些方法
when you're not on-screen?
当你没有在屏幕上吗?
Well, the system might be preparing to animate you
系统可能是你准备动画
coming on-screen,
屏幕上,
When the system animates things,
当系统的东西,
one of the ways it can do it is having you draw one
它可以做的方法之一是让你画一个
orientation, have you draw in the other, and
取向,你画的,
then it kind of moves the bits from one to the other,
那么它的移动从一个到另一个,
That's one kind of animation can do,
这是一种动画可以做,
So you might be off screen, and it's asking you for
所以你可能会关闭屏幕,问你
both of those,
这两个,
So it sends you this twice,
这给你发送两次,
once to get this orientation and draw, and
一旦得到这个方向和画,
then once to get this into orientation and draw,
一旦得到这个为取向和画画,
And then when you come on screen,
当你出现在屏幕上,
it animate you from one to the other,
这动画你从一个到另一个,
So, that's why you can get this at any time
所以,这就是为什么你可以得到这个在任何时间
on screen or off,
在屏幕上或关闭,
Also at any time you could get a low memory warning,
还在任何时候你可以得到一个低内存警告,
And then you're done,
然后你做,
It leaves the heap when it goes off screen if it was
它的叶子堆如果是当它离开屏幕
segued to, as long as it's not itself segued into something,
马上决定,只要不是东西本身的顺利转入,
But when it's done it gets thrown out,
但是写完了就扔掉,
Okay, so I'm gonna show you a demo that
好吧,我将向您展示一个演示
will make all of this a lot more concrete,
会让这一切更具体,
Let me go through the rest of this in case I don't get
让我穿过这我不明白
back to the slides, I think we will, because
幻灯片,因为,我认为我们会
I think we're gonna have time to do this other, topic,
我认为我们会有时间去做这个,话题,
After the demo, I'll come back and
演示结束后,我会回来的
start to talk about memory management, hopefully,
开始讨论内存管理,希望
On Wednesday, extensions, protocols, delegation,
周三,扩展,协议,代表团,
that thing I was telling you you'll need to know for
那件事我告诉你你需要知道
your split view thing, if you wanna do that extra credit,
拆分视图的事情,如果你想做额外的信贷,
And we'll start talking about scroll view,
我们将开始讨论滚动视图,
more complicated object,
更复杂的对象,
On Friday, important one on Friday,
周五,重要的一个周五,
if you want to do the extra credit,
如果你想做额外的信贷,
about performance in the calculator graph,
计算器的性能图,
So you definitely wanna show up for that one,
所以你一定要来,
And then next week we'll start into multi threading,
然后下周我们会开始为多个线程,
table view, a whole bunch of cool stuff,
表视图,很多很酷的东西,
Alright, so let's do this demo here,
好吧,让我们来做这个演示,
I'm gonna go to our face view, same thing we were just in,
我要去我们的脸看来,同样的事情我们只是,
this face it app,
这个面对它的应用,
And I'm gonna drag in a little piece of code I wrote,
我要拖在我写一小段代码,
which I'm gonna show you here,
我要给你们展示,
Let's get out navigator back here, put this in here,
我们离开导航回到这里,把这个在这里,
So I'm just gonna drop this in here,
所以我要把这个在这里,
By the way when you drag in code,
顺便说一下,当你拖动在代码中,
you probably want to do copy items, if needed,
你可能想做复制物品,如果需要,
Otherwise, it's gonna be kind of linked to the other one,
否则,它会链接到另一个,
if you change it in the other place,
如果你改变它在其他地方,
it's gonna be changing here,
它会改变,
Can be kinda causing unexpected results often,
经常会导致意想不到的结果,
I put this in here,
在这里,我把这个
Let's look at this little class I just dropped in here,
让我们看看这个小类我只是在这里,
it's called VCLLoggingViewController,
它叫做VCLLoggingViewController,
It's a subclass of UIViewController,
ui的一个子类,
Logging view controller and it logs the VCL methods,
日志视图控制器日志VCL的方法,
View controller life cycle methods,
视图控制器的生命周期方法,
So it basically just overrides every single one,
所以它基本上只覆盖每一个,
View will appear, view layout subviews away from nib,
视图将出现,离笔尖视图布局视图,
It even tells you when it left the heap,
它甚至告诉你什么时候离开了堆,
It's overriding init here, and
这是压倒一切的init,
it just prints out where it, what happened,
它只是打印出它的地方,发生了什么,
So it just sits there on the console,
所以它只是坐在那里在控制台上,
printing out everything that happened,
打印出发生的一切,
It's a little bit cool,
这有点酷,
because it shows you the instance of each of them,
因为它向您展示了他们每个人的实例,
So you can see instances coming and going,
所以你可以看到来来往往的实例,
as they get segued to, and then come off,
他们会马上决定,然后脱落,
It also kinda indents it over time, so you can, when you
它也有点缩进它随着时间的推移,你可以,当你
click some, you can see a bunch that happen together,
点击一些,你可以看到一群一起发生,
Now the way we're gonna use this is we're just gonna make
现在我们将使用这是我们要做的
this class be the super class of both of our controllers,
这门课是我们两的超类控制器,
So we're gonna make that into a VCL login view controller,
所以我们要让VCL登录视图控制器,
And we're gonna make this into a VCL login view controller,
我们要使它成为一个VCL登录视图控制器,
And right there, you can see why we always wanna call super
在这里,你可以看到为什么我们总是想叫超级
in all of our view control methods,
在我们所有的视图控制方法,
Cuz if we did any of these view controller
因为如果我们做了这些视图控制器
life cycle methods, and
生命周期方法,
we were subclassing from VCL login view controller,
我们从VCL登录视图控制器子类化,
if we don't call super, it not gonna get logged,
如果我们不叫超,它不会被记录,
And it's not unusual to come along later and
这不是不寻常的到来之后
pop the different kind of view controller in between you and
流行不同的视图控制器和你之间
UI view controller,
用户界面视图控制器,
Some view controller that does something like logging or
一些类似的日志或视图控制器
something else,
别的,
All right, so that's it,
好吧,就是这样,
That's all we need to do to make this work,
这就是我们需要做这个工作,
So I'm gonna go ahead and
所以我要继续
run, we'll stick with iPhone 7 plus,
运行,我们将坚持iPhone 7 +,
Let's go ahead and get the console up here,
让我们继续和控制台,
Here we go,
我们开始吧,
This came up, and we're already seeing a lot of
这是,我们已经看到了许多
view controller lifecycle stuff happening here,
视图控制器生命周期的东西发生在这里,
All right, we have our EmotionsViewController and
好吧,我们有EmotionsViewController和
our FaceViewController,
我们的FaceViewController,
these two view controllers get emitted,
这两个视图控制器得到释放,
They come out of the storyboard, and
他们的故事板,
they initialize with this init with coder,
他们与编码器与这个init初始化,
And that's the one that things
这是一个东西
come out the interface builder,
界面构建器出来,
They both get awakeFromNib, you see that?
他们都得到awakeFromNib,你看到了吗?
And then the emotions one, first, gets viewDidLoad,
然后是情感,首先,viewDidLoad,
Then it gets viewwillAppear(animated =
然后它被那些(动画=
That's because we're just starting up our app, so it's
因为我们刚刚开始了我们的应用程序,所以它的
false),
假),
not sliding in on a navigation controller or something,
不滑动导航控制器之类的,
It's just appearing, so it's not animated,
只是出现,所以它不是动画,
Then notice, it gets laid out twice, both at the same size,
注意,它得到了两次,两个在相同的大小,
295 x 414, which is this size right here,
295 x 414,这个尺寸,
It gets look, done twice,
就看,做两次,
Some animation, I don't know wha's going on,
一些动画,我不知道世界是怎么回事,
Again, Why?
再一次,为什么?
why i's doing that,
为什么我这么做,
But you don't care,
但你不在乎,
just be careful that those layouts can happen repeatedly,
只是小心那些布局可以反复发生,
Now here is face view controller, it gets loaded,
这是面对视图控制器,它被加载,
It's told it's going to appear, it will appear,
告诉它会出现,它就会出现,
And it gets laid out once,
它得到了一次,
Then they both get DidAppear, and now they're on screen,
然后他们都得到DidAppear,现在他们在屏幕上,
So this is kind of exactly what you'd expect,
这是你期望什么,
Now let's rotate this thing, so
现在让我们旋转这个东西,所以
that we go to portrait mode,
我们去竖屏模式
And we're not gonna see the master,
我们不会看到主,
We're only gonna see the details here,
我们只会看到这里的细节,
So here, the master disappears,
这里,主消失了,
So this is, see the dash?
这是,看到dash ?
That's what happened when I did that rotation,
这是发生了什么当我做旋转,
So this is all the new stuff,
这是所有的新东西,
Now notice that the EmotionViewController
现在注意到EmotionViewController
immediately is
马上是
told that there's going to be a rotation animation,
告知,将会有一个旋转动画,
And it gets a chance to participate in the animation,
它有机会参与动画,
The FaceView gets re-laid out in its new size,
FaceView一边撑住的新尺寸,
It's tall now, so it gets laid out, so
现在是高的,所以它得到了,所以
it gets viewWillLayoutSubviews,
viewWillLayoutSubviews,
The Emotions Controller is told that it will disappear,
情感控制器被告知它将会消失,
So it's going to disappear,
所以它会消失,
Notice the animated faults, that's cuz the animation in
注意到动画的缺点,因为动画
that rotation case is handled by the rotation animation,
旋转旋转情况下处理的动画,
So it's not sliding in or out but it is getting animated
所以它不是滑动或但它是动画
out of there but by the rotation animation,
但旋转的动画,
Then we have
然后我们有
the face view controller being laid out again,
面对视图控制器再次被提出,
Now we're getting the EmotionsViewControllers
现在我们EmotionsViewControllers
being getting it's chance to
得到它的机会
animate alongside the rotation, right here,
动画在旋转,在这里,
We've got a couple of spurious things here from
我们有一些虚假的东西
the iOS new UIKit, we can get rid of those,
新UIKit iOS,我们可以摆脱那些,
And then the animation ends for both of those controllers,
然后在动画结束这两个控制器,
Make sense?
有意义吗?
Now I'm gonna click this emotions thing, and
现在我要点击这个情绪的东西,
go back to the master and watch what happens,
回到主,看会发生什么,
Okay, so we go back to the master,
好的,我们回到主,
FaceViewController was told it would disappear,
FaceViewController被告知它将消失,
of course, cuz it did, does disappear,
当然,因为那样,消失,
The emotions one is told that it will appear,
情绪被告知它将会出现,
it's laid out in this new tall arrangement,
在这个新的高大的安排,
And then the face view controller told it,
然后面对视图控制器告诉它,
was disappeared and
是消失了,
the emotion view controller was told it disappeared,
情感视图控制器被告知它消失了,
Now let's go, bring one back,
现在我们走吧,带一个回来,
You can see, look, FaceViewController(2),
你可以看到,FaceViewController(2),
A new FaceViewController was created,
创建一个新的FaceViewController,
because we segued to it, so it created it,
因为我们马上决定,所以它创建它,
You see that?
你看到了吗?
And in fact, if we go back and forth, we'll see that we're
事实上,如果我们来回走,我们会发现我们
getting new FaceViewControllers each time,
得到新的FaceViewControllers每一次,
FaceView three,
FaceView三,
And look at the old one's, FaceViewController
,FaceViewController看看旧的
3 left heap, they're gonna thrown out beneath,
3离开堆,他们会抛下,
So I'll be posting all this code,
所以我将发布所有这些代码,
You can drop this logging view controller,
你可以把这个日志视图控制器,
Actually you can drop it into your calculator,
其实你可以把它变成你的计算器,
if you wanted, and try and watch it bring things on and
如果你想要的,试着把东西和看
off screen etc,
屏幕等,
Let's go back to the slides here,
让我们回到这里的幻灯片,
Let's talk about our next topic,
让我们谈论下一个话题,
which is memory management,
内存管理,
We've kind of avoided this topic so far but
迄今为止我们回避这个话题
i's an important topping topic,
我是一个很重要的话题,
If you have a reference counted data structure,
如果你有一个参考数数据结构,
a class tha's the only reference,
一个类那是唯一的参考,
well i's not the only data counting reference structure
我不是唯一的数据计算参考结构
as you'll see in a second,
如您所见,
But if you have a reference counting thing, and it lives
但是如果你有一个引用计数的东西,它的生活
in the heap, how do you know when to get rid of it?
在堆中,你怎么知道什么时候摆脱它?
We saw in that demo I just did the faceview controller
我们看到在这个演示我做faceview控制器
left the heap,
离开了堆,
How did it know to leave the heap?
它怎么知道离开堆呢?
Because we don't do anything to tell it to leave the heap,
因为我们不做任何事情来告诉它离开堆,
We just are using it, and
我们正在使用它
when we're not using it anymore it goes away,
当我们不再使用它它就会消失,
Well, of course, you know one way to make things leave
当然,你知道一个方法让事情离开
the heap, it's called garbage collection,
堆,这叫做垃圾收集,
How many people know what garbage collection is,
有多少人知道什么是垃圾收集,
have heard that phrase before?
以前听过这句话吗?
So, more than half of you, so that's good,
超过一半的你,这样很好,
Runtimes like Java, do garbage collection,
像Java运行时,做垃圾收集,
It's a perfectly fine way to do it,
这是一个完美的方法,
It involves going through the heap and
它包括堆和
kind of marking the use of everything and
标记的使用一切
then sweeping through and
然后席卷
getting rid of stuff that's not used,
摆脱的东西不习惯,
Swift doesn't do any of that, it uses a totally different
迅速不做任何,它使用一个完全不同的
mechanism called Automatic Reference Counting,
自动引用计数机制,
Basically every time you create a var or
基本上每次你创建一个var或
a let that points to something in a heap,
在一堆让指向一些,
Swift goes over somewhere and makes a mark,
斯威夫特在地方和马克,
And another one, there's another one,
另一个,另一个,
And it keeps track of it until there aren't anymore of those
它跟踪,直到没有了
lets and vars,
让和增值,
It erases them as those vars go away,
消除他们的var消失,
Like, maybe they're
也许他们
a var in another object that leaves the heap,
一个var在树叶堆另一个对象,
So now that var is no longer pointing to this other object,
现在,var不再是指向另一个对象,
So it's basically keeping track of all the vars unless
所以这基本上是跟踪所有的var,除非
they point to something in the heap,
他们指出,一些在堆中,
And when no one points to any more,
当没有人指出,
it lets it out of the heap,
它允许堆出来的,
Now why is this good?
现在为什么这么好?
It's very predictable memory usage,
这是非常可预测的内存使用情况,
You know exactly when things are gonna leave the heap,
你知道当事情要离开堆,
They leave the heap as soon as nobody points to them anymore,
他们离开堆就没有人点了,
What's also great about it, is that you almost have to
也是伟大的,那你几乎需要
do nothing in your code to make this work,
什么都不做在您的代码中做这项工作,
It's just automatic,
它是自动的,
That's why it's called automatic reference counting,
这就是为什么它被称为自动引用计数,
You can get involved however,
不过,您可以参与
And the way you can get involved is by influencing
你可以参与的方法是通过影响
the way that arc works,
弧的方式工作,
And you do that with three keywords in Swift
你这样做有三个关键词迅速
called strong, weak and unowned,
所谓的强、弱、无主,
And I actually told you and I was gonna tell you about these
实际上,我告诉你,我是要告诉你关于这些
back in the very first lecture, you remember when we
在第一节课,你还记得我们
made the outlet for display, it was weak,
显示的出口,是弱,
Remember that?
还记得吗?
That's this weak right here,
这里的薄弱,
So the strong, weak and unknown,
因此,强,弱,未知,
So let's talk about each of those,
让我们谈论这些,
Strong, this is normal reference counting,
强,这是正常的引用计数,
If you have a strong var or
如果你有一个强大的var或
strong let to something in the heap, then that thing
强烈的让一些在堆中,那东西
will stay in the heap, as long as that var exists,
会留在堆,只要var存在,
it's strongly holding that thing in the heap,
这是强烈认为事情堆中,
This is the default,
这是默认的,
You don't even ever type this keyword, cuz it's the default,
你甚至不打这字,因为这是默认的,
Every var, unless you say it's weak, is going to be strong,
每一个var,除非你说它是弱,是强,
So it's simple,
所以很简单,
Works magically,
神奇地工作,
Then there's weak,
然后就是软弱,
Now weak is a really interesting keyword in Swift,
现在在迅速、弱是一个很有趣的关键字
When you put weak on top of a var,
当你把弱的var,
it says, well I'm looking at this thing in the heap but
它说,我看这事在堆中
if no one else is interested in the heap then
如果没有其他人感兴趣的堆
you can throw it out of the heap and set me to nil,
你可以扔掉它的堆和我为零,
So weak only works with what type?
所以弱仅适用于什么类型?
>> Optional, >> Optional, exactly,
> >可选> >可选,
cuz you have to be able to set it to nil,
因为你必须能够将其设置为零,
So only optionals can be weak,
所以只能弱,可选
So the display outlet in your calculator,
所以在计算器显示出口,
it was a weak UI label exclamation point,
这是一个弱uilabel感叹号,
which means it was an optional UI label,
这意味着它是一个可选的UI标签,
And so it was weak,
所以它很软弱,
So what does that mean?
所以这是什么意思?
That means if that UI label for
这意味着如果UI标签
some reason ever, everyone else threw it out,
某些原因,其他人把它扔出去,
then that display var would be set to nil, automatically,
然后显示var设置为零,自动
Now, why does that display var set itself weak?
现在,为什么显示var设置本身弱吗?
Why does it say weak?
为什么这么软弱?
Well, because the thing it's pointing to is that view
因为它指向的是这一观点
hierarchy,
层次结构,
The view hierarchy that has all the calculator buttons and
所有的视图层次计算器按钮和
the display and all in there,
显示,都在那里呢,
And if that view hierarchy stops pointing to it,
如果视图层次停止指向它,
that means it's gone, and so the display outlet is no
这意味着它走了,所以显示出口是否定的
longer interested in trying to set numbers in it, and
不再有兴趣尝试设置数字,和
things like that, because it's gone,
类似这样的事情,因为它走了,
So, when you have a var that points into a very strongly
所以,当你有一个var,点到一个非常强烈
held data structure that you completely depend on for
数据结构,你完全依靠了
your semantic meaning to mean anything
你的语义意义
then you can make it weak,
然后你就可以让它弱,
And so we're perfectly fine if that display gets at the nil
所以我们非常好如果显示零
if the view hierarchy no longer points to that UI label
如果UI的视图层次不再指向标签
because it's probably meaningless at that point,
因为它可能是毫无意义的,
So we don't usually use weak that much,
我们通常不使用弱太多,
A lot of times we'll use it to keep from having
很多时候我们会用它来保持的
one object pointing to another strongly and
一个对象指向另一个强烈
having that object point back to this one strongly,
拥有该对象指向这一强劲,
That's very bad situation,
这是非常糟糕的情况下,
That's called a memory cycle,
这叫做一个记忆周期,
That's gonna keep both of those objects in the heap
会让这两个对象在堆中
forever, because there's always gonna be a strong
永远,因为总是会有强劲
pointer to each of them,
它们中的每一个指针,
Cuz they each point to each other,
因为他们每一个点,
So either of them can leave the heap and
所以他们可以离开堆
free up their pointer to the other one,
释放他们的另一个指针,
Unless you set one,
除非你设置一个,
like they're optionally set one to nil or something,
像他们选择性地设置一个零,
So if you had a situation like that,
如果你有这样的情况,
you could use weak to break that cycle by having one
你可以使用弱来打破这种循环
of the pointers be a weak pointer,
指针是一个弱指针,
That would allow it possibly to happen,
,使其可能发生,
And I'm gonna show you an example here of another
我将给你一个例子
case where making that kind of memory cycle is super easy,
情况使这种记忆周期是超级简单,
And that's bad that it's easy,
这是很容易坏,
Because you can get the cycles where things are being
因为你可以得到周期东西在哪里
held in memory,
保存在内存中,
The last one is unowned,
最后一个是无主的,
Unowned means, "Hey, automatic reference counter, Don't worry
无主的意思,“嘿,自动引用计数器,别担心
about this one, I'll take care of it, I'll make sure I never
关于这个,我照顾它,我将确保我从来没有
use it when it's not pointing to something in the heap",
用它当它不是指向堆中”,
This one can be quite dangerous,
这个是很危险的,
We almost never use this,
我们几乎从来没有使用这个,
It would really only be used to break one of these memory
它只会用来打破这些记忆
cycles, and it can only be used to make a memory cycle
周期,它只能用于制造一个记忆周期
when you're 100% sure that you know who's
当你确保你知道谁是100%
using that pointer, because automatic reference counting
使用指针,因为自动引用计数
is not going to be counting it as a strong reference, and
不会是将它作为一个强引用,然后呢
it's also not going to check,
它也不会检查,
And so if you use it, and that thing you're pointing to
如果你使用它,你指着那件事
has left the heap, it will crash your program,
已经离开了堆,它将使程序崩溃,
So that's what unowned is,
这就是无主,
Now, since unowned just crashes your program if you
现在,既然无主程序崩溃如果你
try to use it and it's not in the heap,
尝试使用它,这不是在堆中,
it's not an optional,
这不是一个可选的,
There is no setting to nil,
没有设置为零,
it's always assumed to not be nil,
总是认为不是零,
And if it's ever nil and
如果是零和
that code executes, bam, it crashes,
这段代码执行时,bam,它崩溃了,
So unowned,
所以无主,
I will show you how we use unowned in a moment,
我将向您展示如何使用无主,
It's only to break cycles,
只有打破周期,
Now, closures have an interesting attribute
现在,闭包有一个有趣的属性
about them, which hopefully you read about in your reading
对他们,希望你在阅读中读到的
assignment, that really has a lot to do with this strong,
作业,真的有很多与这个强大的,
weak, and unowned business,
弱,和无主业务,
And then what goes on inside of a closure is that a closure
然后继续在一个闭包是一个闭包
captures all the references inside of it,
截图里面的所有引用,
It captures them, and makes a strong pointer to them,
它捕获它们,使强指针指向他们,
So, if you reference something inside a closure,
所以,如果你引用闭包内的东西,
remember what closures are,
记得什么是闭包,
Open curly braces, and
开放的花括号,
we have some code in there like we had in our
我们有一些代码就像我们已经在我们的
operations table of our calculator brain,
我们的计算器大脑操作表,
So inside that closure,
所以在关闭,
inside those curly braces you reference some reference type,
在这些花括号你参考一些引用类型,
something that's in the heap,
在堆中,
That closure is itself a reference type,
闭包本身就是一个引用类型,
It lives in the heap and
它生活在堆中
it's going to keep a strong pointer to the other thing,
它会保持强指针指向另一件事,
And the problem comes if that other thing has a strong
问题是如果有很强的,其他的事情
pointer back to that closure,
指针回到关闭,
Because now you have a memory cycle,
因为现在你有一个记忆周期,
The closure is keeping that object in and that object that
关闭是对象,对象保持
has a pointer to the closure is keeping the closure in,
有一个指针是保持关闭,关闭
They are keeping each other in memory,
他们彼此保持在内存中,
Now neither of them can ever leave,
现在不可以离开,
It's called a memory cycle and it's really easier memory
它被称为记忆周期和很容易记忆
cycle in a closure, as you'll see,
周期在一个闭包,您将看到,
So, here is an example with our calculator,
这与我们的计算器是一个例子,
Let's say I added a new method to my calculator brain called
我添加了一个新的计算器大脑的方法
addUnaryOperation where I allow people to
addUnaryOperation我允许人们的地方
add new operations to my operations table,
添加新操作我的操作表,
Right now we don't allow that because it's all private,
现在我们不允许,因为这都是私人的,
But let's say I had a public method, addUnaryOperation,
假设我有一个公共方法,addUnaryOperation,
You could add a new operation,
你可以添加一个新的操作,
Wouldn't that be cool?
不会很酷吗?
Yeah, that would be cool,
是的,那将是很酷,
Let's see what it would like for
让我们看看它的希望
a view controller that wanted to, for
一个想要的视图控制器,
example, add a unary operation which is square root, but
例如,添加一个一元运算平方根,但是
it turns the display green,
它将显示绿色,
I call it green square root,
我叫它绿色的平方根,
So, what will it look like to write something like that?
所以,它会是什么样子写点东西呢?
Well, I would call addUnaryOperation,
我叫addUnaryOperation,
give it some symbol,
给它一些符号,
I'm gonna have it look like a green square root but
我要让它看起来像一个绿色的平方根
it's pushing it there but it's kind of what it looks like,
推动它,但它的样子,
And it would pass in the operation for
它能通过操作
green square root,
绿色的平方根,
Now just a couple of cleanup things before that here,
现在几前清理东西,
This is that operation argument to addUnary
这是addUnary操作参数
operation,
操作,
And as we know, we could use trailing
正如我们知道的,我们可以用拖曳
closure syntax here to get rid of that operation colon,
关闭结肠语法来摆脱这个操作,
We just close it, and since the closure is the last
我们关闭它,自闭包是最后一个
argument, we just put it after the end of the parenthesis,
论点,我们只是把它结束后的括号,
Remember that from when I talked about filter and map?
请记住,当我谈到过滤器和地图吗?
So we could do that here, so that cleans it up,
在这里我们可以这样做,这样清洗它,
Also, of course,
当然,也
we could let Swift infer the types here and just use $0,
我们可以让迅速推断这里的类型和使用$ 0,
Everyone understand this code up here?
每个人都理解这个代码?
Could not be simpler, right?
不能简单,对吧?
I'm just adding this Unary operation, green square root,
我只是添加这一元运算,绿色的平方根,
And all it's doing is setting, this, I'm doing this from
和所有的设置,这个,我做这个
my view controller, so it's setting the displays color to
我的视图控制器,设置显示颜色
green And returning square roots,
绿色和返回根,
the same as square root, but the display is just green,
一样的平方根,但显示是绿色的,
Now, this will not compile,
现在,这将不会编译,
Why will this not compile?
为什么这不是编译吗?
Let us look and see why not,
让我们看看为什么不呢,
It's because it's gonna say you have to explicitly say
这是因为它会说您必须显式地说
self dot there because I want you to understand that you
self。因为我想让你明白你
are capturing a strong pointer to yourself In this closure,
在这个闭包捕获强指针指向自己,
So that in case somehow you point to this closure,
所以如果你指向这个闭包,
which our view controller does,
我们的视图控制器,
because our view controller has the calculator brain,
因为我们的视图控制器有计算器大脑,
calculator brain has the operations table,
计算器大脑操作表,
the operations table has this closure in it,
有这个闭包的操作表,
So I'm pointing to that indirectly
我指着间接
from my View Controller, and it's pointing now back at me,
从我的视图控制器,它指向现在回到我,
Self dot, it's gonna capture self,
Self。,它会捕获的自我,
Self is a pointer to myself, my own View Controller,
自我是一个指向自己,我自己的视图控制器,
Now I've created a memory cycle,
现在我已经创建了一个记忆周期,
Yep,
Everyone understand what's going on there?
大家都明白是怎么回事?
The closure lives in the heap,
关闭在堆中生活,
The View Controller lives in the heap,
视图控制器在堆中生活,
They're now pointing to each other,
他们现在指向对方,
The closure's pointing directly to the view
关闭直接指向到视图
controller and the view controller's indirectly
控制器和视图控制器的间接
pointing to the closure through the calculator brain,
指出通过计算器大脑关闭,
through the operations table,
通过操作表,
This operation they've gotta add in,
这个操作必须加入,
So let's talk about how we break this cycle
所以让我们来谈谈我们如何打破这个循环
because since it's so
因为它是如此
easy to do we need to be able to break it easily as well,
容易做到我们需要把它很容易,
Well first thing we're going to do,
我们要做的第一件事,
is we're going to create a special local variable,
我们要创建一个特殊的局部变量,
So closures allow you to before the word in,
所以闭包允许你在这个词之前,
put open square bracket, a list of special variables,
把开方括号,特殊变量的列表,
These are just little local variables that just live for
这些只是小局部变量只活
this closure only,
这个闭包,
Now these variables can have any name,
现在,这些变量可以有名字,
And you can set them to any value you want that's in
,你可以设置你想要的任何值
the scope here,
这里的范围,
So I've created a local variable called me and
所以我创建了一个局部变量叫我
I've set it equal to self,
我已经把它等于自我,
So that's fine, "me" is a local variable,
这样很好,“我”是一个局部变量,
it's going to be of type view controller,
这将是类型的视图控制器,
it's added to myself and so now I can use me in there and
这是添加到自己,所以现在我可以使用我在那里
you already used self so I've replaced self with me,
你已经跟我使用自我我取代了自我,
That doesn't help break our cycle at all,
这并不有助于打破我们的周期,
However, what if I made that me variable,
然而,如果我做了我变量,
not self but me, be unowned?
不是自我,而是我,是无主吗?
If I make that thing be unowned,
如果我做那件事是无主的,
now it's not going to create that strong pointer,
现在它不会创建强指针,
Because me It lives in the heap, but
因为我住在堆,但是
automatic reference counting doesn't reference count it, so
自动引用计数不引用计数,所以
it pays no attention to it,
它没有注意它,
Now what that would mean though,
不过,这将意味着什么
is that if this code were executed, and me,
是,如果这段代码被处决,和我,
which is the view controller cuz I set it equal to self, if
视图控制器因为我把它等于自我,如果
the view controller were out of the heap, this would crash,
视图控制器堆的,这将会崩溃,
But that's perfectly fine here,
但这是非常好,
Do you see why that's fine?
你知道为什么没关系吗?
When would a calculator operation ever be executed
当一个计算器操作还会执行吗
if the view controller is not even in the heap?
如果视图控制器不是甚至在堆中?
It's impossible,
这是不可能的,
The view controller provides all the UI that causes this
视图控制器提供所有UI导致这种
thing to be executed,
被执行,
There's absolutely no way that can happen, so
绝对不可能发生,所以
it's perfectly fine to say unowned here,
是完美的无主,
And that would break the cycle nicely,
这将打破这个循环,
But let's talk about another way to do it,
但让我们来谈谈另一个方法,
By the way, it doesn't have to be called 'me',
顺便说一下,它没有被称为“我”,
I could say 'unknown self' equals 'self',
我可以说“未知的自我”=“自我”,
In other words, the local variable can shadow or
换句话说,局部变量可以阴影或
have the same name as the more global variable 'self',
有相同的名称作为全局变量“自我”,
So I could say unknown self equals self, and
所以我可以说未知的自我=自我,
in fact if I just say unknown self that's the same as
事实上如果我说不一样的自我
saying 'unknown self equals self,
说“未知的自我=自我,
So this is a lot of times how we'll break a cycle,
这是很多时候我们将如何打破恶性循环,
we'll say unknown self and that basically means inside
我们会说未知的自我,这基本上意味着进去
this enclosure, you can assume that self is in the heap,
这个外壳,可以认为自我是在堆中,
Now let's talk about breaking it with weak,
现在让我们来谈谈打破它弱,
So I can also say weak self,
所以我也可以说薄弱的自我,
And that means that self is now a local variable in this
这意味着,自己现在是一个局部变量
closure that's an optional view controller,
闭包是一个可选的视图控制器,
And if it's not, if that view controller is not in the heap,
如果不是,如果视图控制器不是在堆中,
this variable self, which is different from the global cell
这个变量自我,从全球细胞是不同的
is going to be nil,
等于零,
So this is a safe way to do it,
这是一个安全的方法,
But of course since it's an optional,
当然,因为它是一个可选的,
we can't just say self,display,
我们不能只是说自我、显示器、
right there we have to say optional chained self,display,
在这里我们不得不说可选的自我束缚,显示器,
So that if this closure executes and
所以如果这个闭包和执行
the view controller is not in the heap, self question mark
视图控制器不是在堆中,自我问号
will be nil and it will not execute the rest of that line,
将是零,它不会执行剩下的线,
It'll still return the square root,
它仍然会返回平方根,
but it won't turn the thing green because
但是它不会把绿色的东西
this view controller's not even there,
这个视图控制器的根本就不存在,
So that's how we can use weak to do it,
这就是我们可以使用弱,
And sometimes we use weak, and we could create anther
有时候我们使用弱,我们可以创建花药
variable, and often we'll do this,
变量,通常我们会这样做,
This might be the most common way to do it right here,
这可能是最常见的方法,
is to say weak weakself equals self,
是说弱weakself =自我,
And so, weakself is this Argument,
所以,weakself这个论点,
is this local variable inside the closure only
这是局部变量只在关闭吗
that is a weak version of Self,
这是一个自我的弱版本,
Okay, that's kind of clearer
好的,这是一种清晰
what's going on than if you just say weakSelf,
什么比如果你只是weakSelf说,
Then it's like self is an optional, it's weird,
然后就像自我是一个可选的,这很奇怪,
Now at least you have a different variable called
现在至少你有一个不同的变量
weakSelf, all right,
weakSelf,好吧,
Okay, so let's go in the last couple minutes and
好的,让我们走在最后两分钟
just do this in the Calculator,
只是这样做的计算器,
Let's do exactly what I talked about, this green square root,
让我们做什么我谈论,这个绿色的平方根,
I'm just gonna go back to our calculator here,
我要回到我们的计算器,
Where is our calculator?
我们的计算器在哪里?
Here somewhere,
在这里某个地方,
There it is,
在这里,
We haven't seen this code in a while,
我们还没有看到这段代码,
You've seen it a lot,
你见过很多,
I haven't seen it in a long time,
我没见过很长时间,
All right, so here's our calculator, and
好吧,这是我们的计算器
I told you I'm just going to add this new func,
我告诉过你我要添加这个新的函数,
Add unary operation,
加一元运算,
And it's going to take the symbol that we
它需要我们的象征
want to have it be this in there, so it's gonna be like
想要它在那里,所以它会
the green square root, or whatever we call it there,
绿色的平方根,或者我们叫它,
And actually, probably we wanna say something like named
实际上,可能我们要这样说
symbol, that's probably be a little better naming there,
象征,这可能是一个更好的命名,
and that's a string,
这是一个字符串,
And it's going to take an argument,
它需要一个参数,
let's make more space here, which is the operation,
让我们做更多的空间,这是操作,
We don't really need to have an external name because we're
我们真的不需要一个外部的名字,因为我们
probably gonna use trailing closure syntax there to do it,
可能会使用后关闭的语法,
But this is just a Double, returns a Double function,
但这只是一个双,返回一个双重功能,
Hopefully, you're all very familiar by now with using
希望你们都很熟悉现在使用
a function just as a type right there,
就像一个函数类型,
So we have this UnaryOperation,
所以我们有这个UnaryOperation,
And all we need to do to make this work is
和我们需要做这个工作
we have our operations table down here,
我们有下面的操作表,
I'm just gonna say operations sub that symbol =
我只是想说操作子符号=
Operation,unary operation,
操作,一元运算,
where this operation is the argument,
这个操作的参数,
I mean, it couldn't be simpler,
我的意思是,它不能简单,
Really, that was so simple because we built such a good
真的,很简单,因为我们建立了这样一个好
data structure here to store all of our operations,
数据结构来存储所有的操作,
Now notice we have an error here,
注意这里有一个错误,
You see this has an error,
你看这一个错误,
What's it saying?
什么说什么?
Mark this method mutating,
马克这个方法变异,
Okay, why is that?
好了,这是为什么呢?
Well that's because we're changing this operations table
那是因为我们改变这个操作表
so of course that has to be mutating,
当然,变异,
But that's not the only error, we've got another error,
但这并不是唯一的错误,我们有另一个错误,
What's this saying?
这是什么意思吗?
It's saying here that this parameter operation
这里说,这个参数的操作
Is "escaping",
是“逃离”,
What that does that mean, it's escaping?
这是否意味着什么,是逃避吗?
Let's go ahead and fix it,
让我们继续,修复它,
It puts this word in here, @escaping,
它把这个词在这里,@escaping,
Escaping means that this function,
逃离意味着这个函数,
is escaping these curly braces,
是逃避这些花括号,
It is in fact escaping,
它实际上是逃避,
Where is it escaping?
它在哪里逃?
It's jumping into here,
这是跳进来,
Anytime you have a function that you pass in, and
你在任何时候你有一个函数,和
it gets put in some other data structure, in other words,
它被放在其他一些数据结构,换句话说,
it escapes out of the curly braces of the method it's in,
逃出来的花括号的方法,
you have to mark it escaping so that you understand and
你必须转义,这样你理解和标志
swift understands that you are storing that somewhere,
迅速了解你储存的地方,
And that's because it might create a memory cycle
因为它可能会创建一个记忆周期
if you do that,
如果你这样做,
So fix it will automatically remind you about this so
所以解决它会自动提醒你关于这个
you don't have to remember that so much,
你不需要记住,
We've got this nice cool new feature and
我们有这个不错的很酷的新功能
let's go to our view controller and add it,
让我们去我们的视图控制器,并将其添加,
Hey how about we use view did load,
嘿,我们使用viewdidload,
Here's view did load, super dot view did load,
这是viewdidload,超级点viewdidload,
I never want to forget that,
我从来没有想要忘记,
So that's going to happen we're all initialized,
这样会发生什么我们都是初始化,
our outlets are set,
我们的网点设置,
Let's just go ahead and call that addUnaryOperation here,
让我们继续,称之为addUnaryOperation这里,
Let's call it brain addUnaryOperation,
我们叫它addUnaryOperation大脑,
Is that what I called it?
是,我叫它什么?
addUnaryOperation, I don't know why that's not,
addUnaryOperation,不是我不知道为什么,
there it did it,
有了它,
It's just a little slow,
只是有点慢,
addUnaryOperation takes the symbol which is named,
addUnaryOperation需要命名的象征,
And I'm gonna go ahead and
我要和
do that green exclamation point if I can find it here,
做绿色感叹号,如果我可以在这里找到它,
Where is that thing?
那个东西在哪里?
It's probably pictograph, maybe, no,
这可能是象形文字,也许,不,
Anyone know where that would be?
有人知道这是哪里?
Let's try, what's it called, checkmark or something,
让我们试试,这叫什么,选择目录,
There it is,
在这里,
There's our nice symbol right there,
这就是我们美好的象征,
And let's go and add that to our UI as well,
让我们去加入我们的用户界面,
Let's go over here to our story board,
让我们去这里的故事板,
we'll add it instead of Pi,
我们会把它代替π,
So, we'll get rid of Pi instead we'll put that
所以,我们将摆脱π相反我们会把
operation in there,
操作,
What was it called again?
它又叫什么?
Check,
检查,
Oops, two of them,
哦,他们两个,
We've got this new green square root,
我们有了这个新的绿色平方根,
We still have the old square root as well,
我们还有旧的平方根,
But we have to add this operation and
但我们必须添加这个操作
I'm gonna use that trailing closure syntax right there,
我要使用后关闭语法,
And of course we know this is, it's a double takes a double,
当然,我们知道这是,这是一个两双,
And this would be where the stuff goes in there,
这将是这些东西在那里,
But we can let Swift infer this, and just use $0,
但我们可以让快速推断出这个,只使用0美元,
square root of $0,
√$ 0,
So we've done everything except for the green,
我们所做的一切,除了为绿色,
Does everyone agree with this?
每个人都同意这一观点吗?
I'm adding the unary Operation named this symbol and here is
我添加名为这个符号和一元运算
the second argument put on the trailing closure there,
第二个参数穿上后关闭,
So how do we turn it green?
那么我们如何把它绿色的吗?
Well, we just say display,textColor,
嗯,我们只是说显示、输入textColor
Turns out UILabel has a text color = UIColor,green,
原来UILabel文本颜色=用户界面颜色,绿色,
Now, when we put this in here like this,
现在,当我们把这个在这里,
it's gonna complain,
它会抱怨,
Why?
为什么?
Because, reference to property display and
因为,显示和引用属性
closure requires an explicit self dot
关闭需要一个显式的self。
to make the capture semantics explicit,
捕捉语义明确,
This is Swift saying watch out,
这是斯威夫特说小心,
If you do this, you're going to capture self right here,
如果你这样做,你将捕获的自我,
And that is going to create a memory cycle,
这将创建一个记忆周期,
This closure right here,
这个闭包,
which lives in the heap, is pointing to self,
生活在堆中,指向自我,
This addUnary operation is going to cause it,
这addUnary操作将导致,
this closure, to be put in the operations table which is
这个闭包,放在表的操作
pointed to by the View Controller,
指出由视图控制器,
Now they point at each other,
现在他们指着对方,
Let's see, what else did I forget here,
让我们看看,什么我忘记了,
Missing return,
失踪的回报,
Yes,
是的,
Return square root,
返回根,
Everybody cool with that?
大家都明白了吗?
Now, to break that cycle, we could say, unowned self in,
现在,要打破这一循环,我们可以说,无主的自我,
That's one way to break the cycle,
这是一个打破这个循环的方式,
We could say, weakSelf = self, if we do this
我们可以说,weakSelf =自我,如果我们做到这一点
one though we're gonna have to go here and say weakSelf?
虽然我们要去这里,说weakSelf吗?
Either of those will break this cycle,
这些将会打破这个循环,
In your homework, I've updated your homework to say you
在你的家庭作业,我说你更新你的家庭作业
cannot have any of these cycles in your homework,
不能有任何这些周期的作业,
Okay, in assignment three,
在分配三个,
It's in the evaluation criteria down there,
在评估标准,
So I put, posted it on the forum for that too,
所以我说,公布在论坛,
So let's go see if this works,
让我们去看看这个工作,
By the way, what happens if we don't break that cycle,
顺便说一下,如果我们不打破这个循环,
view controllers will just start accumulating in memory,
视图控制器就会积累在内存中,
Because they'll be keeping,
因为他们会保持,
these closures will be keeping them on our memory,
这些闭包将会让他们在我们的记忆,
If you, for example, had a CalculatorViewController
例如,如果你有一个CalculatorViewController
that was being pushed on to you know segue two and
这是被推到你知道segue两
then segue away from, it would not go into out of the heap,
然后segue远离,它不会去堆,
it would stay in heap in that case,
在这种情况下,留在堆
Right here is our calculator,
这里是我们的计算器,
So 81 square root is 9 green square root?
81的平方根是9绿色根?
Woo hoo,
呜呼,
Square root and turned to green,
平方根和转向绿色,
Okay, that's it, see you next time,
好吧,就这样,下次见,
If you guys have any questions, I'm here as always,
如果你们有任何问题,我在这里一如既往,
>> For more, please visit us at stanford,edu,
> >更多内容,请访问我们的斯坦福大学edu,